We can't hold out much longer, sir!
قربان,بيشتر از اين نميتونيم صبر كنيم
General Hummel, you've gotta get us outta here now!
ژنرال هامر, شما بايد ما رو همين الان از اينجا خارج كنيد
I won't let you down. I won't let you down, son.
نميذارم سقوط كنيد نميذارم سقوط كنيد,سر
Goddam it, sir! How long do we have to wait? I've lost 15 men already!
لعنت, قربان!قدر بايد صبر كنيم؟ من قبلا 15 تا از نيروهام رو از دست دادم
Sir, they're lightin' us up like a firestorm!
قربان,اونها دارن روي سر ما آتيش ميريزن
This is General Hummel. You gotta get my men outta there!
ژنرال هامر هستم شما بايد افراد منو از اينجا خارج كنيد
We don't have clearance to go behind enemy lines, sir.
ما اجازه نداريم شت خطوط دشمن بريم, قربان
They're not coming for us, are they, sir?
اونها دنبال ما نميان,مه نه, قربان؟
Congressman Weaver and esteemed members of the Special Armed Services Committee,
جناب ويور عضو كنره و اعضاي محترم كميته سرويسهاي نيروهاي ويژه
I come before you to protest a grave injustice.
من قبل از شما اومدم تا به اين بي عدالتي اعتراض كنم
Aim!
هدف
It has to stop.
بايد جلوش رفته بشه
I miss you so much.
دلم برات خيلي تن شده
There's something I've gotta do, Barb.
يه كاري هست كه بايد انجام بدم,بارب
Something I couldn't do while you were here.
كاري رو كه وقتي تو اينجا بودي نميتونستم انجام بدم
I tried. You know I tried everything.
من سعيم رو كردم ميدوني كه همه جوره سعي كردم
And I still don't have their attention.
و هنوزم نتونستم متوجهشون كنم
Let's hope this elevates their thinking.
اميدوارم اين قضيه ديدشون رو باز كنه
But whatever happens,
اما هر اتفاقي كه بيفته
please don't think less of me.
منو فراموش نكن
Marine, inform the garrison C.O...
ماروين ...به ادان اطلاع بده
that General Hummel's coming on board with a security inspection team.
كه ژنرال هامل همراه با تيم بازرسي امنيتي دارن ميان
Yes, sir. Sir, it's an honour having you, sir.
بله, قربان. قربان,با تقديم احترام
Ya know, at least we can get some...
...ميدوني, حداقل ما ميتونيم مقداري
- A long time before guard meeting, huh? - Yeah, I'll tell ya.
وقت زيادي تا تغيير ست داريم, ها؟ آره, آره
I got the access card. We've got 30 minutes till those darts wear off.
كارت ورود رو بدست آوردم تا از بين رفتن اثر تيرها 30 دقيقه فرصت داريم
Move it!
حركت كنيد
The access card, sir.
كارت ورود, قربان
Let's do it.
شروع كنيد
Twenty-four hundred magazine check.
Twenty-four hundred magazine check.
- Man, it's wet out there! - Check me through, will ya?
مرد, ه باروني مياد اين وسط رو امضاء كن, باشه؟
Clear!
امنه
- I want 16, Major! - Move it!
شونزده تاشون رو ميخوام, سررد بجنبيد
Evac! Seal the door!
اواك در رو قفل كن
- No! - Come on, man!
نه! زودباش, مرد نه
- Seal it! - Help!
قفلش كن كمك كنيد
Let me outta here! Oh, God!
بذاريد بيام بيرون! اوه, خداي من
Let me out! Let me out!
بذاريد بيام بيرون! بذاريد بيام بيرون
Clear out. Get outta here!
جمع کنيد از اينجا ميريم
Sorry.
متاسفم
Let's move out.
بياييد بريم
Two more cc's of acetylene chloride.
دو سي سي استيلن كلرايد بيشتر
- That'll be five dollars, Isherwood. - You suck.
نج دلار شد, ايشر وود تو يه احمقي
You guys have too much time on your hands.
شما به ها خيلي زمان در اختيارتونه
Yes! She's here! Bring it to me now. Thank you, Phil!
آره! اون اينجاست! بدش به من ممنون فيل
What's that? Why'd you get it sent here?
اون ي هست؟ را اونو اينجا فرستادن؟
Carla wouldn't approve. She thinks it's dumb to spend $600 on an L.P.
كارلا موافق نبود اون فكر ميكنه هزينه كردن 600 دلار براي ال ي بي معنيه
Carla's right. Why don't you just spend $13 on a CD, man?
حق با كارلاست. را يه سي دي 13 دلاري نخريدي,مرد؟
First of all, it's because I'm a Beatlemaniac.
اول از همه براي اينکه من يه خورده ديوونه ام
And second, these sound better.
ثانيا اينطوري بهتره
Could be serious. Could be sarin gas.
بايد جدي باشه بايد از سارين باشه
A dog out of JFK caught a whiff of something in this package...
...يه س متوجه يه يزي داخل اين بسته شده
postmarked to a Bosnian refugee camp.
كه داشته به كم ناهندان بوسنيايي فرستاده ميشده
It could be detergent, or it could be sarin gas.
ميتونه مواد شوينده يا از سارين باشه
Bosnian refugee camp?
كم ناهندان بوسنيايي؟
Half a million Serbians reside in the U.S., Marvin. Serbians don't like Bosnians.
نيم ميليون صرب در آمريكا اقامت دارن, ماروين صربها از بوسنيايي ها خوششون نمياد
You guys wanna get suited up?
شما به ها ميخوايد لباس بوشيد؟
- You bring the cockroaches? - Got 'em.
تو باخودت سوسك آوردي؟ ببينشون
We have air lock, Stanley. You're all set to go.
ما آماده ايم, استانلي بريد
October 1, 0900 hours.
اول اكتبر,ساعت 9
Agent Stanley Goodspeed, Agent/Trainee Marvin Isherwood...
مامور استانلي ود اسيد مامور تريني ماروين ايشر وود
initiating exam of wooden crate.
آزمايش روي جعبه رو شروع ميكنيم
Suspicion of sarin gas inside.
مشكوكيم كه داخلش از سارين باشه
- Marvin, sarin is a... - G.B. aerosol.
...ماروين, سارين يك - G.B. aerosol
That is correct.
درسته
Now, let's see. We have some dirty magazines.
خب بذار ببينيم ند تا مجله كثيف داريم
Stone Age Cave Girls in the Raw.
دختراي عصر حجر
Kinky. And, uh... Not a good sign.
...مو فرفري. و آه علامت خوبي نيست
Hello, little baby doll.
سلام, عروسك كوولو
Lookit, Stan.
ناش كن, استان
- Hi there, - Marvin! - Stanley.
سلام به ها ماروين استانلي
- Hi, Stan. - Shit! Move back! Move back!
سلام, استن لعنتي! برو عقب! برو عقب
- I want the exhaust. - Hang on, guys.
ميخوام هوا رو تخليه كنم تحمل كنيد, به ها
We'll have that room clear in 50 seconds! You're gonna be okay.
ظرف 50 ثانيه هواي اتاق اك ميشه براتون مشكلي ايجاد نميشه
Jesus Christ!
يا عيسي مسيح
Okay, I've got some bad news and some really bad news.
خب, ند تا خبربد و واقعا بد دارم
The bad news is that the gas is corrosive and it's eating our suits.
خبر بد اينه كه اين از داره لباسهاي ما رو ميخوره
- It's all over my hand, man! - The really bad news...
اون روي تموم دست منه, مرد ...خبر واقعا بد اينه كه
is there's enough C-4 explosive and poison gas to blow the whole chamber...
ماده منفجره سي 4 و از سمي به اندازه كافي ...براي انفجار اين اتاق
- and kill everybody in the building. - Detonation too heavy. - Everybody, out of the room now!
و كشتن همه افراد اين ساختون وجود داره همه افراد سريعا از اتاق برن بيرون
Seal us inside.
ما رو تنها بذاريد
- Where are the sprinklers, Lonner? - The acid's eating my su...
آب اشها كجا هستن, لونر؟ ...اين اسيد داره لباس منو
It's eating my fucking suit! All right? Shit!
اون داره لباس لعنتي منو ميخوره باشه؟ لعنتي
- Just wash us off! - Where are my sprinklers?
فقط ما رو بشور آب اشهاي من كوشن؟
We're working on it. It's coming. It's just a flow problem.
داريم روش كار ميكنيم. داره مياد فقط يه مشكل در فشار آبه
Well, that's a pretty big friggin' problem, Lonner. Fix it now!
خب,اون مشكل واقعا بزريه, لونر زودباش درستش كن
- We're working on it! How much time do you have on that detonator? - A minute ten.
داريم روش كار ميكنيم قدر زمان براي خنثي كردن بمب داري؟ ده دقيقه
- Look at this! - We're gonna have the room clear.
اينو ببين ما ميخوايم اين اتاق را امن كنيم
- Tell 'em to take the atropine, now! - The atropine, Isherwood.
آتروين رو برداريد, همين الان آتروين, ايشر وود
- What? - Where's my water, Lonner? One minute!
ي؟ آب اش من ي شد, لونر؟ يه دقيقه صبر كن
- Marvin, the atropine, now! - Inject it in your heart before your suit melts.
ماروين, همين الان آتروين رو بردار قبل از اينكه لباست ذوب بشه اونو توي قلبت تزريق كن
Shit!
لعنتي
Make him take his dose.
به اونم بده
- Where's that water? - Get that away from me!
آب اش من ي شد؟ اونو از من دور كن
Come on, Phil, fix it for Christ's sake!
زودباش, فيل, بخاطر خدا درستش كن
- Take the atropine now, Stan, - We're fucked.
استان بخاطر خدا همين الان آتروينت رو بردار دهن ما سرويس شد
The poison's mixing.
ماده سمي داره تركيب ميشه
What the fuck are you waiting for, Stanley? You take the fucking needle now!
منتظر ي هستي, استنلي؟ بايد همين الان دارو رو تزريق كني
- Fuck! Shit! Oh, fuck, shit! - Forty seconds!
لعنتي! لعنتي! اوه, لعنتي, لعنتي هل ثانيه
If that suit melts... If you die, we all die!
...اه لباست ذوب بشه اه تو بميري, همه ما خواهيم مرد
Inject your heart and then diffuse the bomb!
دارو رو توي قلبت تزريق كن بعدش بمب رو خنثي كن
- Come on, just do it, Stan! - Shit! What if I miss my heart? I can't see shit!
يالا, اينكار رو بكن استن لعنت! اه قلبم از كار بيفته ي؟ من نميتونم ببينم
- Do it now! - Look how big this is. You want me to stick this into my heart?
همين الان انجام بده ببين قدر بزره.شما ميخوايد كه اينو توي قلبم فرو كنم؟
- Are you fucking nuts? - The sprinkler's coming! It's coming!
شما دويونه شديد؟ آب اش داره راه ميوفته راه افتاد
Okay, here we go, man!
خيلي خب, ما اينجاييم مرد
Sprinkler activated.
آب اش فعال شد
How much time left?
قدر زمان مونده؟
Twenty seconds!
بيست ثانيه
We're not gonna make it.
از عهدش برنمياييم
Fifteen.
ونزده ثانيه
Oh, come on.
اوه, يالا
Clear!
خنثي شد
Get me the fuck out of this gas chamber!
منو از اين اتاق از لعنتي بياريد بيرون
I almost stabbed myself in the heart with this thing.
من تقريبا داشتم قلبم رو با اين يز سوراخ ميكردم
Please lock me away
:ترجمه و تنظيم hamilton hamilton37@37.com
- Stan? - Hey, darlin'.
استن؟ سلام, دارلين
Hi, baby.
سلام, سر
Here inside where I hide with my loneliness
من اينجا خلوت كرده بودم
I had such an interesting day today.
امروز برام روز فوق العاده اي بود
Yeah, I had kind of an interesting day myself.
آره, منم يجوري روز جالبي داشتم
Oh, okay, you go first.
خب باشه اول تو بو
Oh, just some terrorists decided to send a little care package, box of goodies,
اوه, فقط ندتا تروريست تصميم رفته بودن يه جعبه قاقا لي لي بفرستن
which had to be neutralized before blowing up the office.
مجبور شديم قبل از اينكه دفتر رو بفرسته هوا خنثاش كنيم
So I took the rest of the day off.
خب من امروز رو مرخصي رفتم
Glass of wine, little guitar. Just relaxing.
يه ليوان مشروب, يه خورده يتار فقط براي آرامش
- Wow! - I mean it, honey. The world is being Fed-Ex'd to hell on a handcart.
واوووو منظورم اينه که, عزيزم.دنيا مثل يه بانک فدرال ميمونه که روي رخ دستي بسمت جهنم ميره
I really believe that anyone who's even thinking about having a child in this world...
...من واقعا معتقدم كه هركسي كه فكر به دار شدن رو بكنه
is coldly considering an act of cruelty.
واقعا ظلم كرده
I know, I'm rambling, I'm complaining. I'm sorry.
ميدونم, دارم رت و لا ميم دارم غر ميزنم. متاسفم
- What's your news, baby? - I'm pregnant.
خب خبراي تو يه؟ من باردارم
I'm sorry?
ببخشيد؟
I'm pregnant.
من حامله هستم
- Really? - Yeah.
واقعا؟ آره
- Wow! - Is that all you're gonna say, is "wow"?
واووو تموم يزي كه ميخواستي بي,"واوو" بود؟
- You're pregnant? - Three weeks.
تو بارداري؟ سه هفتست
How do you know? I mean, h-how do you know?
طوري فهميدي؟ منظورم اينه كه,طوري فهميدي؟
Blue! Just turned blue so I went to the doctor.
آبي شد! اون آبي شد خب منم رفتم يش دكتر
- Well, you didn't mean what you just said, did you? - When?
خب, تو از جمله اي كه فتي منظوري داشتي, مه نه؟ كي؟
Uh, just right now when you were talking about bringing a child into the world...
..اه, همين الان كه داشتي درباره بدنيا آمدن به به اين دنيا
and having it be an act of cruelty.
و ظلم كردن صحبت ميكردي
- I meant it at the time. - Stanley, at the time? You said it seven and a half seconds ago.
منظورم اون موقع بود استنلي, اون موقع؟ تو همين ند ثانيه قبل اينو فتي
Well, gosh!
خب, عجب
Kind of a lot's happened since then. Look, we're not even married.
از آنموقع تاحالا اتفاقات زيادي افتاده ببين, ما حتي ازدواج هم نكرده ايم
- I know. It's funny you should mention that. - It's funny?
ميدونم. مسخرست تو بايد در جريان قضيه قرار ميرفتي مسخرست؟
- Do you love me? - Of course I love you.
تو منو دوست داري؟ البته كه دوستت دارم
Good.
خوبه
- Will you marry me? - Whoa! Whoa! Wai... Hey, Marriage Police, pull over!
با من ازدواج ميكني؟ ...وايسا! وايسا! وايسا هي, ليس ازدواج, بزن كنار
Come on, Stanley. I'm proposing to you right now.
يالا, استنلي من دارم الان بهت يشنهاد ازدواج ميكنم
The Rock is the most famous and was the most feared prison ever built.
راك مشهورترين و ترسناك ترين زنداني بود كه تا حالا ساخته شده
Is it really true that there's never been an escape?
واقعيت داره كه حتي يك نفر هم از اونجا فرار نكرده؟
Ah, that's true. From 1936 until '63 when the prison closed,
...آه, درسته. از سال 1936 تا سال 1963
there were 14 attempts.
هارده بار تلاش شد
No one is believed to have made it to shore, alive at least.
هي كسي باورش نميشد به ساحل برسن,اما حداقل زنده موندن
No, uh, h-h-hey, hey, fellas. I'm sorry, but tourists are not allowed back here.
نه, آه, ه-ه--هي,هي,.ببخشيد اما توريستها اجازه ورود به اينجا رو ندارن
- I don't really give a shit! Do you give a shit? - No.
من واقعا نميخوام بهت توهين كنم تو بمن توهين ميكني؟ نه
- Come here, fruity. - Move!
بيا اينجا راه بيفت
- Hey, girls? Hi. You all havin' a good time? - Yeah.
سلام, به ها؟ سلام بهتون خوش ميذره؟ آره
Will you do something for me? It's really, it's really important.
يه كاري برام انجام ميديد؟ اون خيلي خيلي مهمه
I need you to tell your teacher that you need to get back on the boat and go home right now.
ميخوام كه به معلمتون بيد كه بايد سوار قايق بشيد و همين الان بررديد به خونه
Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to Broadway!
خانمها و آقايون به برود وي خوش آمديد
This cell block housed...
..اين سلولها
the most awesome scum in America.
ترسناك ترين سلولها در آمريكا هستن
Ladies and gentlemen, l, Ranger Bob,
خانمها و آقايون من, رنجر باب
cordially invite you to become inmates of Alcatraz, temporarily, of course.
از صميم قلب از شما دعوت ميكنم تا در آلكاتراس ساكن بشيد البته بطور موقت
On the line!
به خط بشيد
Pretty tight quarters, aren't they, huh?
سلولهاي كاملا محكمي هستن,مه نه,هاه؟
Like being a caged animal.
مثل قفس حيوانات ميمونن
Spend a couple of years in there...
...ندسال موندن در اينجا
- What's the matter, fellas? Something wrong with the tour? - The tour's over, Bob.
ه خبر شده؟ مشكلي در رابطه با تور هست؟ ردش تموم شد,باب
What kind of fucked-up tour is this?
اين جور تور مسخره ايه؟
General Hummel, Captains Frye and Darrow reporting, sir.
ژنرال هامل, كايتان فراي و كايتان دارو زارش ميدن, قربان
Welcome to The Rock, gentlemen. Land the choppers on the back side and deploy as planned.
به راك خوش آمديد, آقايون هليكوتر رو در قسمت شتي فرود بياريد و آماده اجراي نقشه بشيد
- Aye, aye, sir. - Aye, aye, sir. Move out!
اطاعت, اطاعت,قربان اطاعت, اطاعت, قربان. راه بيفتيد
I'm not allowed to carry a gun.
من بهتون اجازه ندادم كه با خودتون اسلحه حمل كنيد
Oh, you're not allowed to carry a gun? I got a goddam gun.
اوه, شما اجازه حمل اسلحه نداديد؟ من يه اسلحه دارم
If I'd've known this was gonna happen, I'd have brought my motherfuckin' gun! Help!
اه ميدونستم اين اتفاق ميخواد بيفته,تفن لعنتي رو خريده بودم كمك
All right, gentlemen, this'll be our new home. Tom, I want my command centre right here.
بسيارخب آقايون,اينجا خونه ي جديد ماست تام,ميخوام مركز فرماندهي همينجا باشه
- I want Coms up. - Roger that, sir.
راش بندازيد بله قربان
Put the satellite over there. I wanna be up at 1600.
ماهواره رو بذار اونجا ميخوام تا 1600 بره بالا
Let's move it.
بريم
- Systems up. - Possible penetration point in the shower room.
سيستم راه افتاد نقطه نفوذ احتمالي در اطاق واشين ميباشه
- We're setting anti-intrusion. - I brought a personal touch, sir.
داريم سيستم ضدنفوذ را راه ميندازيم من يه وسيله دست ساز آوردم, قربان
It's an anti-motion trembler device. It's custom-made.
اين يه دستاه لرزشي ضد حركته.اون دست سازه
Nobody knows about it and nobody expects it.
هيكسي دربارش يزي نميدونه و كسي انتظارش رو نداره
- What's it do? - We head-fake 'em with the laser beam.
كارش يه؟ كلاهك جعلي با رتو ليزر
And then if they disturb Mr Backup here, we own 'em.
و اه اونها خرابش كنن نسخه شتيبان من اينجاست
Ladies and gentlemen, you're being detained against your will.
خانمها و آقايون ...از اينكه حبس شديد
For that, I apologize.
ازتون عذرخواهي ميكنم
It is not our intention in any way to harm you.
هدف ما اين نيست كه به شما آسيب بزنيم
You will not be detained one minute longer than is necessary for us to complete our mission.
بعد از كامل شدن ماموريت ما شما حتي 1 دقيقه هم در حبس نخواهيد موند
Attention on deck!
!خبردار
Stand easy, men.
راحت باشيد
Make no mistake about it, gentlemen, we are now in harm's way.
هي اشتباهي نكنيد آقايون, ما الان در مسير خطرناكي قرار داريم
For Major Baxter and l, this is the last campaign in a career datin' back to Tet '68.
براي سررد باکستر و من اين آخرين عمليات هستش
Likewise for Captain Hendrix, Gunnery Sergeant Crisp,
همينطور براي کايتان هندريکس و روهبان دوم کريس
who cut their teeth under my command in Desert Storm.
که در عمليات طوفان صحرا تحت فرمان من بودن
Captain Frye, Captain Darrow, this is my first operational situation with you and your men.
كايتان فراي, كايتان داروف اين اولين عمليات من با شما و نيروهاتون هستش
And I have to say, thus far your conduct reflects your reputations.
و بايد بم, عملكرد شما منعكس كننده شهرت شماست
- Thank you, General. - Thank you, sir.
ممنون, ژنرال ممنون, قربان
We have achieved our position through poise, precision and audacity.
ما با درستي و ثبات و جسارت به اين موقعيت رسيده ايم
To this we must now add resolve.
بايد الان تصميمون رو بيريم
We'll be branded as traitors, the gravest capital crime.
ما به عنوان خائنين و بزرترين جانيان بشر شناخته خواهيم شد
Punishable by death.
مجازاتمون مر خواهد بود
A couple hundred years ago,
ند صد سال قبل
a few guys named Washington, Jefferson and Adams...
...ند نفر به اسمهاي واشينتون , جفرسون و آدامز
were branded as traitors by the British.
توسط دولت بريتانيا بعنوان خائن شناخته شدند
And now they're called patriots.
و الان به اونها ميهن رست مين
In time, so shall we.
الان ما هم همين وضع رو داريم
God willing, in less than 48 hours...
...به خواست خدا,در كمتر از 48 ساعت
you will evacuate this island in gunships under cover of hostages and V.X. gas warheads.
شما اين جزيره را در وشش روانها و كلاهكهاي از وي ايكس ترك ميكنيد
Your destination: a non-extradition treaty country.
:مقصد شما يه كشوريست با معاهده منع استرداد مجرمين
You will each be paid a fee of $1 million for services rendered.
به هر كردوم از شما 1 ميليون دلار رداخت ميشه
But you can never again set foot on your native soil.
اما هرز نميتونيد اتون رو توي خاك كشورتون بذاريد
- Can you live with that? - Yes, sir!
ميتونيد با اين شرايط زندي كنيد؟ بله, قربان
The men of Marine Force Recon...
نيروهاي ...نيروي دريايي ريکون
are selected to carry out illegal operations throughout the world.
عملياتهاي غيرقانوني را در سراسر دنيا انجام ميدادن
When they don't come home,
وقتي اونها به خونه برنميردن
their families are told fairy tales about what happened to them...
درباره اتفاقي كه براي اونها افتاد براي خانوادهاشون داستان ردازي كردند
and denied compensation.
و منكر رشادتهاي اونها شدن
Well, I have choked on these lies my entire career!
خب, من راه اين دروغها رو در تمام زنديم بسته ام
Well, here and now the lies stop!
خب, همينجا و الان دروغها متوقف ميشن
God be with all of you. Man your positions, men.
خدا بهمراه شما افراد به موقعيتشون برردن
This is FBl Director Womack.
مدير اف بي آي , ووماك هستم
Director, be advised.
جناب مدير, عاقل باش
Eighty-one, I say again,
هشتاد و يك دوباره ميم
81 civilians are under my control as of this moment.
در اين لحظه 81 نفر تحت كنترل من هستن
You are to take measures to assure this remains a need-to-know classified fact.
شما بايد اقداماتي انجام بديد كه اين قضيه بصورت محرمانه باقي بمونه
Who is this?
شما كي هستيد؟
Mr Director, you have a very serious problem.
آقاي مدير, شما مشكل خيلي حادي داريد
A battery of V.X. gas rockets is presently deployed...
...راكتهاي مجهز به از وي ايكس در حال حاضر آماده هستن
to deliver a highly lethal strike on the population of the San Francisco Bay area.
تا جمعيت بسيار زيادي از سواحل سان فرانسيسكو را آلوده كنن
- I will call again at 0100 hours to state my demands. - I want to know who I'm talking to.
ساعت 1 براي فتن درخواستهام مجدد زن ميزنم ميخوام بدونم با كي دارم صحبت ميكنم
This is Brigadier General Francis X. Hummel, United States Marine Corps, from Alcatraz.
من ژنرال فرانسيس ايكس هامل,تفندار دريايي ايالات متحده از آلكاتراز هستم
Out!
تمام
- I'll cancel your reservations. - Get the Pentagon.
تمام قرارهاتون رو كنسل ميكنم برو نتاون
And call the San Francisco office. It seems Alcatraz was just reopened.
به دفتر سان فرانسيسكو زن بزن بنظر ميرسه آلكاتراس دوباره باز شده
Last night General Hummel, using brutal but nonlethal force...
شب ذشته ژنرال هامل,با استفاده از داروهاي بيهوش كننده
under the guise of a security exercise, walked off with 15 V.X. poison gas rockets.
تحت عنوان تمرين امنيتي, 15 تا از راكتهاي از سمي وي ايكس رو بسرقت برده
He lost one of his own men in the process.
در اين عمليات اون يكي از نيروهاي خودش رو هم از دست داده
That's General Hummel in Vietnam. I think he was a major at the time.
اين ژنرال هومل در ويتنامه فكر ميكنم در آن زمان سررد بود
Three tours in Vietnam, Panama, Grenada, Desert Storm.
سه ماموريت در ويتنام, اناما, رانادا, طوفان صحرا
Three Purple Hearts, two Silver Stars...
سه نشان شجاعت ...دو ستاره نقره اي
and the Congressional Medal of...
...و مدال كنره
Jesus! This man is a hero!
خداي من اين مرد يه قهرمانه
Well, I think "legend" might be a better description, Mr Sinclair.
خب, من فكر ميكنم عبارت "افسانه" بهتر باشه,جناب سينكلر
Well, now we can add kidnapping and extortion to his list of accolades.
خب,الان بايد آدم ربايي و اخاذي رو هم به ليست افتخارات ايشون اضافه كنيم
Mr Sinclair, General Hummel is a man of honour.
آقاي سينكلر, ژنرال هومل يه مرد محترم هستن
General, it's him.
ژنرال, خودشه
Frank, it's Al Kramer.
فرانك, ال كريمر هستم
Hi, Al, how you doin'?
سلام,ال, طوري؟
I don't know, Frank. Ah, why don't you tell me.
من نميفهمم, فرانك اه, را بهم نميي
Got a lot of very, very worried people here, Frank.
حاضرين در اينجا خيلي خيلي نران هستن, فرانك
I'll come straight to the point.
مستقيم ميرم سر اصل مطلب
Eight-three Force Reconnaissance Marines have died under my various commands.
هشتاد وسه تا از تفنداران دريايي تحت فرمان من جون خودشون رو از دست دادن
Forty-seven in northern Laos and southern China.
هل وهفت تا در لائوس شماي و ين جنوبي
Southern China? We never admitted we sent troops into China.
ين جنوبي؟ ما هرز موافق اعزام نيرو به ين نبوديم
Who is this? Identify yourself.
شما؟ خودتون رو معرفي كنيد
White House Chief of Staff Hayden Sinclair, General.
رئيس دفتر كاخ سفيد هايدن سينكلر, ژنرال
- How old are you, Chief of Staff Sinclair? - I'm 33.
رئيس دفتر جناب سينكار شما ند سال داريد؟ سي و سه سال
Well, Mr Sinclair, you've probably got no fucking idea what I'm talking about.
خب, آقاي سينكلر, شما احتمالا نميدونيد من دارم درباره ي صحبت ميكنم
By your ninth birthday, I was runnin' black ops into China,
وقتي شما 9 سالتون بود,من توي ين عمليات اجرا ميكردم
and my men were responsible f-for over 200 enemy kills.
و نيروهاي من مسئول مر 200 تا از دشمنها بودن
Al, put some rigging tape over Mr Sinclair's mouth. He's wasting my time.
ال, دهن اين آقاي سينكلر رو ببند اون داره وقت منو تلف ميكنه
Ah, you want to continue, Frank?
اه, ميخواي ادامه بدي,فرانك؟
Remember Operation Desert Storm?
عمليات طوفان صحرا رو يادت مياد؟
Those surgical hits made by our smart bombs, covered so well on CNN?
اون اهدافي كه توسط بمبهاي هوشمند ما مورد اصابت قرار رفت و خيلي خوب هم توسط سي ان ان وشش خبري داده شد؟
It was my men on the ground that made those hits possible by lasing the targets.
اونها نيروهاي من بودن كه توسط اون بمبها مورد هدف قرار رفتند
Twenty of them were left to rot outside Baghdad after the conflict ended.
بعد از اين اشتباه 20 تا از نيروهاي من خارج بغداد رها شدند تا بوسند
No benefits were paid to their families.
هي وجهي به خانواده هاي اونها رداخت نشد
No medals conferred.
هي مدالي بهشون داده نشد
These men died for their country, and they weren't even given a goddam military burial.
اونها بخاطر كشورشون مردن ولي حتي يه مراسم خاكساري هم براشون نرفتن
The situation is unacceptable. You will transfer $100 million...
اين وضعيت قابل قبول نيست ...شما بايد مبلغ 100 ميليون دلار
from the Grand Cayman Red Sea Trading Company account to an account I designate.
از حساب شركت تجاري درياي سرخ به حسابي كه بهتون ميدم منتقل كنيد
From these funds, reparations of $1 million will be paid...
..از اين مبلغ 1 ميليون دلار به عنوان غرامت
to each of the 83 Marines' families.
به هر يك از 83 خانواده سربازان داده ميشه
The rest of the funds I will disperse at my discretion.
مابقي ول را هم من به صلاحديد خودم توزيع ميكنم
Do I make myself clear?
حرفم رو واضح فتم؟
Except for the Red Sea Trading Company. What is that?
كماني تجاري درياي سرخ يه؟
- Identify yourself. - This is FBl Director Womack, General.
خودت رو معرفي كن مدير اف بي آي ووماك هستم, ژنرال
It's a slush fund where the Pentagon keeps proceeds from illegal arms sales.
اون ول كثيفيه كه نتاون از طريق فروش غير قانوني سلاح بدست مياره
Jesus, Frank! This is classified information.
خداي من, فرانك اين اطلاعات محرمانست
You alert the media, I launch the gas.
ار به رسانه ها خبر بدي منم از رو خش ميكنم
You refuse payment,
اه رداخت ول رو رد كني منم از رو منتشر ميكنم
You've got 40 hours, till noon day after tomorrow to arrange transfer of the money.
شما 40 ساعت وقت داريد, تا ظهر س فردا بايد ترتيب انتقال ول رو بديد
I am aware of your countermeasure. You know and l know it doesn't stand a chance.
من از اقدام متقابل شما خبردارم شما و من ميدونيم اين قضيه شانسي نيست
Hummel from Alcatraz. Out.
هومل از آلكاتراس تمام
All right. We have to identify the hostages and contact each of their families.
بسيارخب. ما بايد روانها را شناسايي و با خانوادهاشون تماس بيريم
Uh, tell 'em somethin'. Make up a story, and we've got to keep this undercover.
اه, يه يزي بهشون بو يه داستان درست كن,ما بايد اين قضيه رو مخفي نه داريم
If this comes out, the city of San Francisco will be in chaos. I am talking anarchy.
اه يزي درز كنه, سان فرانسيسكو دار هرج و مرج ميشه من دارم درباره اغتشاش حرف ميزنم
Wait a minute, wait a minute. What is the potential casualty rate...
يه لحظه صبر كنيد, يه لحظه صبر كنيد ...ميزان تلفات احتمالي
for a single rocket armed with V.X. poison gas, General Peterson?
به ازاي هر راكتي كه به از سمي وي ايكس مسلح بشه قدره ژنرال ترسون؟
- Sixty or seventy. - Well, that's, that's not so bad.
شصت يا هفتاد خب, خيلي هم بد نيست
- Thousand. Seventy thousand dead! - Oh.
هزار. هفتاد هزار مر و مير اوه
One teaspoon of this hits the floor, it's lethal up to a hundred feet.
يه قاشق از اين ماده سمي اه روي زمين بريزه در حدود 100 ا آلودي و مر و مير داره
One teaspoon of this shit detonated in the atmosphere...
...اه يه قاشق از اين ماده لعنتي در اتمسفر منفجر بشه
will kill every living organism in an eight-block radius.
تمام موجودات زنده رو در شعاع 8 بلوكي ميكشه
Get the point?
متوجه شديد؟
Uh, what did Hummel mean by your countermeasure, General?
اه, منظور هومل از "اقدام متقابل شما" ي بود؟, ژنرال؟
Standard poison is countered by napalm. It burns it up, consumes it upon detonation.
سم استاندارد در تقابل با بنزين غليظ شدست.بنزين باعث آتش رفتن و انفجار آن ميشه
Now, the problem with V.X. poison gas is...
..الان, مشكلي كه با از سمي وي ايكس داريم اينه كه
that it's designed specifically to withstand napalm.
طوري طراحي شده كه در برابر مواد آتش زا مقاومه
That's where, uh, thermite plasma comes in. General Peterson?
ما لاسماي ترميت رو داريم. ژنرال ترسون؟
Thermite plasma incendiary systems can burn hot enough to consume V.X.,
لاسماي ترميت سيستم آتش زايي هستش كه ميتونه بقدري داغ بشه كه از وي ايكس رو از بين ببره
but they're still in the test phase; it's not operational.
اما هنوز در مرحله آزمايشي هستش عملا تست نشده
Hummel knows this. We are dealing with one smart son of a bitch.
هومل از اين قضيه اطلاع داره.ما با يه آدم باهوش لعنتي سروكار داريم
What's it gonna take to equip a flight of F-18s with thermite plasma...
...نظرتون يه كه ما يه جننده اف 18 را ظرف 36 ساعت آينده
within the next 36 hours?
به لاسماي ترميت مسلح كنيم؟
- An act of God. - Excuse me?
به اميد خدا ببخشيد؟
All right, we can try.
بسيارخب, ميتونيم تست كنيم
But I strongly urge you to consider the use of this as a secondary initiative.
اما قويا ازتون ميخوام از اين مورد بعنوان اقدام ثانويه استفاده كنيد
Then we have to go to our primary initiative. Uh, Admiral?
س بايد روي اقدام اوليمون كار كنيم. اه, دريالاسلار؟
Sir, I'd like to bring in our SEAL ground commander, Commander Anderson.
قربان, من نظرم روي فرماندهي زميني هستش, فرمانده اندرسون
Mr Womack, who is your best chemical/biological man?
آقاي ووماك, بهترين بيوشيميست شما كيه؟
- Oh, that's interesting. - Oh, yeah. - That's very compelling.
اوه, جالبه اوه, آره خيلي اجباريه
- You like my pigtails? - Oh, yeah, the pigtails are very naughty.
تو از موي بافته خوشت مياد؟ اوه, آره, مو بافته ها خيلي شيطون هستن
Naughty. Naughty.
شيطون. شيطون
Just the Amaretto cream with peach sorbet persuasion.
فقط خامه آمارتتو با شربت هلو
- This isn't happening. - No, Stan, don't answer it.
ولش كن نه, استن, جواب نده
- This isn't happening! - No, just don't answer it. It's okay.
نه, فقط جوابش رو نده. باشه
- I have to. It's the office, baby. They know I'm home. - No.
بايد جواب بدم.از ادارست. اونا ميدونن من خونه ام نه
How could they possibly know that you're home?
اونا طور ممكنه بدونن تو خونه اي؟
It's the FBl.
اف بي آي هستش
Stanley!
استنلي
Goodspeed. Uh, yeah. O-Okay, yeah.
وود اسيد هستم اوه, بله. باشه, بله
I'll be, I'll be down, yeah, downstairs in ten minutes.
ميام, ميام ايين, آره ده دقيقه ديه ائينم
No, you won't.
نه, تو نميري
- I have to go to San Francisco. - No, you don't.
مجبورم برم سان فرانسيسكو نه, مجبور نيستي
Stanley, no, you do not have to go to San Francisco.
استنلي, نه, تو مجبور نيستي بري سان فرانسيسكو
Are you kidding me right now? You need to stay here and talk to me about things.
منو دست انداختي؟ تو بايد اينجا بموني و درباره يه سري مسائل صحبت كنيم
- I've got to go, baby. - Oh! I am Catholic! Do you realize that?
من بايد برم اوه! من يه كاتوليك هستم ميفهمي؟
I am pregnant and I am unmarried. And this causes a serious problem for me.
من حامله هستم و ازدواج هم نكردم. اين قضيه ميتونه براي من مشكل جدي درست كنه
I cannot believe you.
نميتونم بهت اعتماد كنم
No, no.
نه, نه
I love you. I will marry you.
دوستت دارم باهات ازدواج ميكنم
I just didn't plan on this, that's all.
فقط آماديش رو نداشتم,همش همين
- Come to San Francisco. - Really?
باهام بيا سان فرانسيسكو واقعا؟
Yeah, I'm sure it's just a training exercise.
آره, مطمئنم اون ميتونه يه تمرين آموزشي باشه
Check into the hotel. Order up some champagne.
ميريم هتل شاماين سفارش ميديم
- And we'll finish what we started? - Exactly.
و كاري رو كه شروع كرديم رو تمومش ميكنيم؟ دقيقا
- Baby, you're gonna marry me? - You know it.
سر, تو ميخواي با من ازدواج كني؟ ميبيني
You're gonna marry me!
تو ميخواي با من ازدواج كني
- Oh, honey, come on. Just a really quick one. - Oh, oh, I gotta go now.
اوه, عزيزم, زودباش اوه, اوه, الان بايد برم
A nighttime airdrop incursion is out due to the full moon.
حمله هوايي شبانه به دليل ماه كامل شدني نيست
Likewise a frontal seaside attack.
همينطور حمله از كنار دريا
If we're compromised and shots are fired, Hummel might launch.
اه ما شناسايي بشيم و تيراندازي صورت بيره هومل ممكنه از رو شليك كنه
Our only alternative is an attack from within the prison.
تنها زينه باقيمانده برامون حمله از داخل زندان هستش
We penetrate the island through the tunnels under the prison buildings undetected...
ما از طريق تونلهايي كه زير ساختمونهاي زندان شناسايي نشده اند به جزيره نفوذ ميكنيم
and emerge in its centre; that way we can jump the Marines from behind.
اين تونلها در مركز زندان بهم ميرسن از اين طريق ميتونيم از شت به تفندارها حمله كنيم
And if we're lucky, take their rocket positions without a shot fired.
و ار موفق بشيم,ميتونيم موقعيت راكتها رو بدون شليك حتي يك لوله بدست بياريم
I don't understand. You-you've studied the architectural plans?
نميفهمم. شما-شما طراحي معماري خونديد؟
They're useless. Alcatraz has been ripped up and rebuilt for years.
اونا بي فايده هستن. آلكاتراس سالها قبل خراب شده و دوباره بازسازي شده
- Under there is a maze of shit. - Well, there's no question, gentlemen.
اون زير ر از ي و خمه خب, سوالي نيست, آقايون
We need firsthand intelligence of the tunnel systems.
ما به اطلاعات دست اول درباره سيستم تونلها نياز داريم
- So what about the former warden? - Died in 1979.
از رئيس قبلي ه خبر؟ در سال 1979 مرده
All the guards we contacted were useless.
تمام نهبانهايي كه باهاشون تماس رفتيم بدرد نميخوردن
Um, there is someone who I think can help us.
ام, فكر ميكنم يه نفر هست كه بتونه بهمون كمك كنه
- This is for the sake of national security. - No!
اين بخاطر امنيت مليه نه
It's the sake of national security that got us here in the first place 33 years ago.
بخاطر امنيت مليه كه همه ما اينجا جمع شديم
I knew! I knew someday this would come back to bite us.
ميدونستم! ميدونستم اين قضيه يه روزي به خودمون برميرده
Forget it! He does not exist.
فراموش كن اون وجود نداره
He does exist! We just chose to forget him for 30 years.
اون وجود داره! فقط ما انتخاب كرديم كه اونو 30 سال فراموش كنيم
- We locked him up and threw away the key. - Oh, and a lot of goddam good it did us.
ما اونو قفل كرديم و كليدش رو هم دور انداختيم اوه, اون خيلي به درد ما خورده
He broke out of two maximum security prisons. And if he hits the streets...
اون از دو تا زندون با امنيت بسيار بالا فرار كرده ...و اه اون اش به خيابون برسه
He's not gonna hit the streets, Jim.
اون اش به خيابون نميرسه جيم
Thirty years ago he was a highly trained SAS operative.
سي سال قبل اون بالاترين دوره هاي امنيتي رو ذرونده
He is my age now, for Christ's sake!
اون الان همسن منه بخاطر خدا
I have to get up three times a night to take a piss.
من مجبورم كه شبها 3 بار بيدار بششم تا برم دستشوئي
We can't risk letting him out.
ما نميتونيم ريسك كنيم بذاريم اون بياد بيرون
He's a professional escape artist.
اون استاد فرار كردنه
- Gosh. Neat, uh... - Yeah. - Neat, neat plane.
...عجب.تميزي, آه آره هوايماي تميزي
Dr Goodspeed. James Womack.
دكتر وود اسيد جيمز ووماك
- A pleasure to meet you, sir. - Welcome. - Thank you.
از ديدنتون خوشحالم, قربان خوش آمديد ممنون
You come very highly recommended.
خيلي تعريف شما رو كردن
B.A. Columbia; M.A., PhD, Johns Hopkins.
داراي مدرك بي آي از دانشاه كلمبيا داراي دكتراي آم اي از دانشاه جانز هاكينز
Biochemistry, toxicology.
بيوشيميست, سم شناسي
Well, I'm one of those fortunate people who like my job, sir.
خب, من يكي از اون آدماي خوشبختي هستم كه كارش رو دوست داره, قربان
Got my first chemistry set when I was seven. Blew my eyebrows off.
اولين مدرك شيمي رو وقتي 17 سال داشتم رفتم ابروهام ريختش
We never saw the cat again. Been into it ever since.
"
What do you know about V.X. gas?
درباره از وي ايكس ي ميدوني؟
Liquid. Failed pesticide discovered by a mistake in 1952.
مايع هستش. آفت كش مخربي كه اشتباها در سال 1952 كشف شد
Uh, actually, it's kind of like champagne that way.
آه, در واقع اون يه نوع شاماين هستش
The Franciscan monks thought they were making white wine.
راهبه هاي فرانسيس تصور ميكردن آنها شراب سفيد ساخته اند
Somehow the bottle carbonated. Voila! Champagne.
بهرحال يجور نوشيندنيه هورا! شاماين
- And then the whole thing just... - The gas, Dr Goodspeed.
...و بعدش تمام اون فقط منظورم ازه, دكتر وود اسيد
It's very, very horrible, sir.
اون خيلي خيلي خطرناكه قربان
It's one of those things we wish we could disinvent.
يكي از يزهايي كه آرزو ميكردم هي وقت اختراع نميشد
This isn't a "train" exercise, is it?
اين يه تمرين "آموزشي" نيست,مه نه؟
No, Dr Goodspeed, it's not a training exercise.
خير دكتر وود اسيد اين يه تمرين آموزشي نيست
- Hello, sir. - Good morning, Director.
سلام قربان صبح بخير, جناب مدير
This is Ernest Paxton, agent in charge of the West Coast operation.
ايشون ارنست كستون هستن,مامورارشد عمليات كرانه غربي
- Dr Goodspeed. - Pleasure to meet you. - How do you do, sir?
دكتر وود اسيد از ديدنتون خوشحالم حالتون طوره,قربان؟
It's been a fairly interesting day so far. The prisoner's here. Shall we?
روز خيلي خوبي بايد باشه.زندانيها اينجا هستن
Now, my boys, they haven't been able to find a file on this guy. Who is he anyway, sir?
تا الان افراد من نتونستن هي رونده اي از اين يارو يدا كنن اين يارو كيه قربان؟
His name is John Mason, a British national...
اسمش جان ميسونه ...با مليت انليسي
incarcerated on Alcatraz in 1962, escaped in '63.
در سال 1962 در آلكاتراس زنداني بود و در سال 1963 از اونجا فرار كرد
I was under the impression that no one ever escaped Alcatraz, sir.
من تصور ميكردم تا حالا كسي از آلكاتراس فرار نكرده قربان
Paxton, don't argue!
كستون, بحث نكن
This man has no identity, not in the United States or Great Britain.
اين مرد هي هويتي نداره, نه در ايالات متحده و نه در انليس
He does not exist. Understand?
اون اصلا وجود نداره متوجه شدي؟
I want one thing: how he escaped The Rock.
:يه يزي رو ميخوام بدونم اون طوري از "راك" فرار كرد؟
Specifically the route he took through the island's bowels.
بخصوص راهي كه اون از مسير ر و ي خم جزيره رفت
- The papers are in order, sir. - We're prepared to offer him a full pardon.
بره ها آماده هستن, قربان ما بهش عفو كامل يشنهاد كرديم
And Paxton, no strong-arming Mason. I know him too well.
كستون من اونو خوب ميشاسم
Well, if you know him, then why don't you question him?
اه اونو خوب ميشناسين س را ازش نميرسيد؟
No, he'll remember me. I don't want his anger clouding the issue.
نه,اون منو ميشناسه نميخوام خشم اون اين قضيه را تحت تاثير قرار بده
All right, I'll take care of him.
بسيارخب,من خودم انجامش ميدم
Mr Mason, I'm Special Agent in Charge, Ernest Paxton.
آقاي ميسون, من مامور ويژه, ارنست كستون هستم
In charge of what? Fucking me over for another three decades?
مامور ويژه ي؟ ميخواهيد 30 سال ديه دهن منو سرويس كنيد؟
I don't know anything about your previous matters. I'm here because...
من درباره مسايل ذشته شما يزي نميدونم ...من اينجا هستم براي اينكه
a special situation exists that we feel you might be able to help us with.
يك موقعيت خاصي يش اومده كه احساس كرديم ممكنه شما بتونيد كمكمون كنيد
Well, what might that be?
خب, اون امكان ي هست؟
I've been in jail longer than Nelson Mandela, so maybe you want me to run for president.
من بيشتر از نلسون ماندلا توي زندان بودم نكنه ميخوايد من در خدمت دولت باشم
- Not exactly. - Mmm, a pity.
نه دقيقا ام,حيف شد
I feel rather like Alcamedes.
ما احساس ميكنم مثل آلكامدس هستم
- Who? - Alcamedes. He was imprisoned by his king in ancient Greece.
مثل كي؟ آلكامدس.اون بوسيله ادشاه يونام قديم زنداني شد
- Like Sir Walter Raleigh. The same fate. - James the First.
مثل سر والتر رالي سرنوشتي مشابه جيمز اول
Even someone as bright as you must be aware that, uh,
حتي آدمي به باهوشي شما بايد اينو بدونه, آه
there's a certain pattern emerging here.
يك الوي خاصي اينجا درحال ديدار شدنه
Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn?
آلكساندر زولزنيستين؟
Yeah, I heard of him. Didn't he play hockey for the fuckin' Red Wings?
آره, دربارش شنيدم.اون براي تيم بالهاي قرمز لعنتي هاكي بازي نميكرد؟
- That's the chap. - Get this straight, pops.
اون يه معامله كرد بريم سر اصل مطلب
I don't like you any more than you like me.
بهمون اندازه كه تو از من خوشت نمياد منم از تو خوشم نمياد
But I'm here to make you a legitimate offer.
اما من اينجام تا بهت يه يشنهاد قانوني بكنم
You wanna hear what I have to say or not?
ميخواي به يشنهادم وش كني يا نه؟
By all means, dear Paxton. By all means.
با تمام وجود, كستون عزيز با تمام وجود
We got a problem in a place that I think you know.
يه مشكلي توي جائيكه فتي داشتيم
There's a hostage situation on Alcatraz.
روانيري در آلكاتراس
- Hostage? - Eighty-one tourists.
روان؟ هشتاد و يك توريست
The Rock has become a tourist attraction?
راك يه منطقه توريستي شده؟
Why don't we cut the shit, huh? You know The Rock.
را اين مزخرفات رو تموم نميكنيم, ها؟ تو "راك" رو ميشناسي
- You broke out. - Yes, successfully.
تو از اونجا فرار كردي آره, با موفقيت
Yeah. So why don't you do yourself a favour while you're helpin' us?
آره. خب را به خودت يه لطفي نميكنه در حاليكه به نفعته با ما همكاري كني؟
I mean, it'd be nice to get out of jail while you're still vertical.
منظورم اينه كه,خوب ميشد اه از زندان آزاد ميشدي
Hmm? While you got a little lead left in your pencil.
Hmm? While you got a little lead left in your pencil.
While I'm considering your offer,
در حاليكه دارم به يشنهادتون وش ميكنم
I want a suite in the Fairmont Hotel.
يه سوئيت توي هتل فيرمونت ميخوام
You know I'm here to cut you a deal.
من اومدم اينجا تا باهات يه معامله بكنم
I am not here to bend over and take it up the ass from you.
نه اينكه خم بشم و بهت سواري بدم
Here. Here's a quarter.
اينجا. اينجا يه اقامتاهه
Do yourself a favour. Call your lawyer. You're goin' back to jail.
به خودت يه لطفي بكن. به وكيلت زن بزن تو به زندان برميردي
- Y-You're sending him back to jail? - I'm not sending him anywhere.
ش-شما ميخوايد اونو بفرستيد زندان؟ من اونو جايي نميفرستم
I'm just givin' him somethin' to think about.
من فقط داشتم يه يزي بهش ميدادم تا بهش فكر كنه
With all due respect, sir, I don't think we have time...
با كمال احترام, قربان ...من فكر نميكنم ما وقت داشته باشيم
for him to just sit around and think about it.
تا اون اينجا بشينه و بهش فكر كنه
- Oh, really? - No, Goodspeed's right.
اوه, راستي؟ نه, حق با وود اسيده
- You go talk to him. - Me? - Yes.
تو ميري باهاش حرف ميزني من؟ آره
- Sir, I'm not qualified for that. - You're an FBl agent!
قربان, من براي اينكار آموزش نديدم تو مامور اف بي آي هستي
- W-What is your specialty again? - Chemical weapons.
دوباره بيد تخصص شما يه؟ سلاحهاي شيميايي
Don't mention that!
بهش فكر نكن
- You want me to lie? - Yeah, lie.
شما ميخوايد كه من دروغ بم؟ آره,دروغ بو
We got less than 24 hours. Give it a shot.
ما كمتر از24 ساعت فرصت داريم يه بار تلاش كن
Okay.
باشه
Hi.
سلام
I'm an agent with the, uh, uh, F-Federal...
من مامور, آه, ...اه, ف-فدرال
FBl. Uh...
...اف بي آي هستم.آه
- Eh, well, my... I'm Stanley Goodspeed. - But of course you are.
اه, خب, من... من استنلي وود اسيد هستم البته كه هستيد
Well, at least he got his name right.
خب, حداقل اسمش رو راست فت
- Of course I am. Huh. - And you have an emergency.
البته كه هستم. هاه و توهم يه وضعيت اضطراري داري
That's right.
درسته
And you need my help.
و به كمك من احتياج داري
Exactly right.
دقيقا همينطوره
- Coffee. - No, no, I'm fine. Thank you.
قهوه نه, نه,ممنون. ممنون
Offer me coffee.
بو برام قهوه بيارن
Oh, yes! Well, that was, in fact, gonna be my next...
اوه,بله! خب, اون, ...در حقيقت, ميخواستم بعدش
Can we get a cup of coffee in here, please?
ميشه يه فنجون قهوه برامون بياريد, لطفا؟
And offer to take these off.
و بو كه اين دستبندها رو باز كنن
Mr Mason, really.
واقعا, آقاي ميسون؟
- All kidding aside. - As a gesture of your good faith.
شوخي به کنار براي نشان دادن حسن نيتتون
- Prisoner requests to have his handcuffs taken off. - No, no, no, no.
زنداني درخواست داره كه دستبندهاش رو باز كنيد نه, نه, نه, نه
Why don't you go ahead and have his handcuffs taken off, please?
را نميري جلو و دستبندهاش رو باز نميكني,لطفا؟
Well, I guess that's one way to go.
خب, حدث ميزنم يه راه بيشتر نداريم
This is a pardon and release contract from the Attorney General's office.
اين حكم آزادي و عفو شماست كه از دفتر ژنرال آتورني صادر شده
Now, it makes you a free man provided you cooperate.
حالا,در قبال همكاريتون شما آزاد ميشيد
So if you'll just, uh, sign,
خب اه شما فقط, آه امضاش كنيد
uh, at, uh, where it says...
آه, اونجا, آه ...اونجا كه نوشته
- "Signature"? - That's... Yes. "Signature."
"امضاء" همون... آره.امضاء
Well, timeo danaos et dona ferentis.
خب, "جمله يوناني
"l fear the Greeks even when they bring gifts."
"من از يونانيها ميترسم حتي وقتيكه برام هديه ميارن"
Oh, an educated man!
اوه, يه آدم تحصيلكرده
That rules out the possibility of you being a field agent.
اين قواعد خارج از توانايي يک عامل ميدانيه
In point of fact, I am a field agent, Mr Mason.
در حقيقت,من يه مامور ميداني هستم, آقاي ميسون
- Really? - Yes.
واقعا؟ بله
- In which field? - Antiterrorism.
در كدوم زمينه؟ ضد ترروريست
Then you're trained in weaponry, explosives and mortal combat.
س شما بايد در زمينه اسلحه مواد منفجره و دريري تن به تن آموزش ديده باشين
Well-trained.
خوب هم آموزش ديدم
Then it's the Fairmont Hotel.
قرار هتل فيرمونت سرجاشه
Okay.
آره
I want a suite, a shower, a shave...
من يه سوئيت ميخوام دوش بيرم,اصلاح كنم
and the feel of a suit.
و يه دست لباس ميخوام
May I also suggest, uh, a haircut?
شايد بنظر من, آه,يه سلموني؟
- Am I out of style? - Unless you're a 20-year-old guitarist from Seattle.
قيافه بده؟ مه اينكه شما يه يتاريست 20 ساله از سياتل باشيد
- It's a grunge thing. - Grunge?
اون يه يز "رونج" هستش رونج؟
Yeah, well, uh, uh... Okay, thank you very much.
...آره, خب, آه, آه بسيارخب, خيلي ازتون ممنونم
All right. Call the Fairmont. Close the floor if necessary, but I want him sealed off.
بسيارخب. به هتل فيرمونت زن بزن اه لازمه اون طبقه رو ببند ميخوام شديدا تحت نظر باشه
And he gets two hours max.
حداكثر 2 ساعت زمان ميبره
- Great job, Goodspeed. - Why didn't you throw in a trip to Tahiti while you were at it?
كارت خوب بود, وود اسيد
- I'll deliver this to the Attorney General. - Uh, no, you'll give it to me.
من خودم اينو به ژنرال آتورني تحويل ميدم اوه, نه, شما اونو ميديش به من
And take Attorney Reynolds outside. There's a car waiting for you. Thank you.
رينولد آتورني بيرونه.يه ماشين منتظرتونه.مرسي
That's a signed federal document, sir. Isn't that illegal?
اون يه بره رسمي امضا شده ست,قربان اين كار غيرقانوني نيست؟
You're not acquainted with the full facts, Goodspeed.
شما تمام حقايق رو نميدونيد, وود اسيد
With all due respect, sir, I'd like clarification. I gave that man my word.
با كمال احترام, قربان,ميخوام منو در جريان بذاريد من شخصا بهش تعهد دادم
Damn it! You're on a need-to-know basis, and you don't need to know.
لعنت! تو كافيه فقط مقدمات رو بدوني لازم نيست كه همه ي رو بدوني
It's, uh, it's, eh, kind of curious, but, uh,
اون, آه, اون, اوه عجيبه, اما, اوه
Sir Walter Raleigh, Alcamedes, Solzhenitsyn,
سر والتر رالي آلكامدس, زولنتيسين
they, um, well, they were all wrongfully imprisoned.
اونها, ام, خب,همه اونها اشتباهي زنداني شده بودن
Womack! Now, why am I not surprised, you piece of shit!
ووماك! الان, اصلا تعجب نميكنم, تو يه آشغالي
Eh, peace! Peace!
اه, تسليم! تسليم
Hey, we're not home. Leave a message.
سلام, خونه نيستم يغام بذاريد
Hi, darling, it's, uh, it's me.
سلام, عزيزم, من,آه منم
Uh, listen, don't come to San Francisco.
اوه, وش كن, نيا سان فرانسيسكو
I repeat, do not come
تكرار ميكنم, نيا سان فرانسيسكو
- Stanley, no! - Carla. - Wha...
استنلي, نه كارلا ..ي
- Like hell I'm not coming!
به جهنم نميام
Wait. Car...
...صبركن.كارل
Who's Carla? And why don't you want her to come to San Francisco?
كارلا كيه؟ را ازش خواستي كه نياد سان فرانسيسكو؟
You're on a need-to-know basis, and you don't need to know.
تو فقط بايد مقدمات رو بدوني لازم نيست همه ي رو بدوني
Watch it, he'll bite you.
نياش كن, اون تو رو از مييره
Good. Mobile Command is fully operational.
خوبه.دستور عمليات صادر شده
- We'll be there in approximately two hours. - I'm not armed, sir.
ما تقريبا 2 ساعت ديه اونجا هستيم من مسلح نيستم, قربان
- I am unarmed, sir. - Well, where's your issue?
من سلاح ندارم, قربان خب, سلاحت كجاست؟
I left it in my, uh, my sock drawer.
من اونو خب توي كمد لباسهام جا ذاشتم
A gun?
تفن؟
For what? You're a chemical freak.
براي ي ميخواي؟ تو يه شيميداني
No, I'm a chemical super-freak, actually. But I still need a gun.
نه,راستش من يه فوق تخصص شيمي هستم اما با اين حال يه اسلحه لازم دارم
Give him a goddam gun.
يه تفن بهش بده
Have you fired one of those things since the Academy?
از وقتي دانشاه رفتي تاحالا با يكيشون تيراندازي كردي؟
- Wear some - If you're going to - Flowers in your hair
يه يزي بوش اه ميخواي بري ل سرت
Don't forget to wear flowers in your hair
يادت نره كه ل سرت رو بزني
- If you're going
اه ميخواي بري
- To San Francisco
به سان فرانسيسكو
- You're sure to meet some - You're gonna meet - Gentle people there
تو مطمئنا يه سري رو ملاقات ميكني تو ند نفر رو ملاقات ميكني آدماي نجيب اونجا هستن
- Some gentle people there - And you come for...
...و تو مياي بخاطر
If you're going to San Francisco
اه ميخواي بياي سان فرانسيسكو
Uh, uh, room service?
اوه, آه, بخش سرويس اتاقها؟
Ah, listen. This is the penthouse. Do you do snacks, drinks? Huh?
آه, وش كنيد. اينجا نت هاوسه شما اسنك و نوشيدني داريد؟ها؟
Hello!
سلام
- You the barber? - No. Stylist.
شما آرايشر هستيد؟ نه.من متخصص مد هستم
Barber.
آرايشر
- Just clippers. No scissors. - No scissors? You've got to be kidding me, no scissors!
فقط ماشين مو زني. قيي ممنوعه بدون قيي؟ منو دست انداختيد؟ بدون قيي
I mean, did they tell Picasso, "No brush"?
:منظورم اينه كه, آيا اونها به يكاسو فتن بدون قلم؟
With scissors, this man could kill you.
اه قيي يشت باشه,اين مرد ميتونه تو رو بكشه
I can't cut anyone's balls off with a trimmer now, can I?
من نميتونم تخمهاي كسي رو با يه آرايشر ببرم, ميتونم؟
Why don't we do this outside? Get some sun.
را بيرون اينكار رو نميكنيم؟ يه خورده آفتاب بير
Oh, who did this to you? This is just not right. In fact, it's nasty!
اوه,كي اينكار رو باهات كرد؟ اصلا درست نيست راستش زنندست
Well, it's a grunge thing.
خب, اون يه رونجه
Well, it's some kind of thing.
خب, اون يه نوعي از يزه
Do you think we have time for a sea kelp protein pack and maybe some colour?
آيا فکر ميکنيد وقت براي خوردن صدف دريايي و آفتاب رفتن داريم؟
No.
نه
Okay. Not very nice, is he?
باشه اون يارو خيلي دلسب نيست, مه نه؟
No, he's not.
نه, نيست
'Cause I'm leavin'
'Cause I'm leavin'
Hey, somebody ordered it. Can't let it go to waste.
هي, يه نفر اونو سفارش بده نميتونيم بذاريم هدر بره
- Don't know when I'll be back again - Don't you ever stop eatin'?
نميدونم دوباره كي برميردم نميخواي دست از خوردن بكشي؟
Not when it's free.
نه وقتيكه اون مفتيه
- We're supposed to be on duty. - Hey, don't worry. He's an old man.
تصور ميشه كه ما الان در حال انجام وظيفه ايم هي, بيخيال. اون يه يرمرده
The boss is watchin' 'im. Come on, have... Try some of this lobster.
رئيس مراقب همه ي هست. يالا,بخوريد از اين خرن امتحان كنيد
- Mm-hmm. - My secretary here will settle the bill.
ام-اه..م منشيم صورتحساب شما رو رداخت ميكنه
So what do you have in store for me, Womack, when this is over?
وقتي اين قضيه تموم بشه, ووماك,ي برام داري؟
You'll get your life back, Mason.
تو برميردي سر زنديت,ميسون
But you could've given me my life back years ago.
اما تو نتونستي زندي سالهاي قبل منو بهم برردوني
- Why should I trust you now? - You've got my word.
را بايد الان بهت اعتماد كنم؟ تو بايد روي حرف من حساب كني
Will you shake on it?
ميتونيم دست بديم؟
- Freeze, mister! - Oh, man!
تكون نخور, آقا اوه,مرد
Help!
كمك
Drop the gun or I drop your boss.
اسلحت رو بنداز والا رئيست رو رت ميكنم ايين
You will not!
تو اينكار رو نميكني
Get!
برو اونور
- He's getting very heavy. - Then pull him up.
اون داره خيلي سنين ميشه س اونو بكش بالا
Please don't!
لطفا اينكار رو نكن
Help! Shit!
كمك كن! لعنتي
Come on, have a scallop. Come on, catch.
يالا, وش ماهي بخور زودباش, بير
You hoist him!
خودت بكشش بالا
Help! Help! Help!
كمك! كمك! كمك
- Where's Mason? Where is Mason? - Help! Hang on!
ميسون كجاست؟ ميسون كجاست؟ كمك! طاقت بيار
- Where's Mason? - Mason's gone! - Gone?
ميسون كجاست؟ ميسون رفت رفت؟
Clear.
امنه
Living room's clear!
اطاق نشيمن امنه
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
اوه, خداي من! اوه, خداي من
All units, this is Caretaker. We have a Signal Six. He's in the hotel!
به تمام واحدها, سررست صحبت ميكنه اعلان وضعيت اخطار 6 اون توي هتله
Okay, I don't wanna know nothin'. I never saw you throw that gentleman off the balcony.
باشه, نميخوام يزي بدونم. من هي وقت شما رو نديدم
All I care about is, a-are you happy with your haircut?
من مراقب همه ي هستم آيا از اصلاح موهاتون راضي هستيد؟
Easy!
آروم باشيد
Watch it, you fuckhead, you're gonna pull my arm out!
مراقب باشيد احمقا اين بندها رو از دستم باز كنيد
Watch out!
مراقب باشيد
Oh, no!
اوه, نه
Watch it!
بريد كنار
- Hey, watch it! - He's over there!
هي, مراقب باشيد اون اونجاست
Hey!
هي
This is my Humvee. I don't want any dings, dents or scratches, or I'll have your ass. Hey!
اين ماشين هاموي منه.نميخوام هي خطي روش بيفته
Hey! Stop! Hey!
هي! وايستا! هي
Hey, I was inside the bedroom with Jack Powell!
هي, من همراه جك اول توي حموم بودم
Hey, call the guard! Go!
هي, به نهبانها خبر بده! برو
FBl.
اف بي آي
Move!
بريد كنار
Whoa! Whoa!
وايستا! وايستا
Suspect is in a black Humvee, heading west on California.
مظنون سوار يك هاموي مشكي هستش داره به سمت غرب كاليفرنيا ميره
Speed approximately 70 miles per hour.
با سرعت تقريبي 70 مايل در ساعت
Get out of the way!
از سر راه بريد كنار
I want a net put on this son of a bitch, you hear me?
من ميخوام اين كثافت رو به دام بندازم,شنيديد؟
This guy's hittin' every fuckin' thing in sight tryin' to block us!
اين يارو داره هري سر راهشه رو داغون ميكنه سعي كنيد متوقفش كنيد
I hope you're insured!
اميدوارم كه بيمه باشيد
Oh, well, why not?
اوه, خب, را كه نه؟
You're goin' down!
تو داري از ا درمياي
Hello?
الو؟
I'm only borrowing your Humvee!
من فقط ماشينتون رو قرض رفتم
Information? San Francisco?
اطلاعات؟ سان فرانسيسكو؟
Uh, Jade Angelou. That's A-N-G...
آه, جيد آنجلو ...به اين صورت آ-آن-جي
Welcome aboard, y'all. How y'all doin' today?
همي خوش آمديد امروز ميخوايد يكار كنيد؟
Hang on!
وشي دستت
Holy shit!
لعنتي
Whoa-oa!
وايستا-هي
Oh, no!
اوه, نه
We're gonna crash! Save yourselves!
ما داريم تصادف ميكنيم خودتون رو نجات بديد
Oh, my baby!
اوه, كوولوي من
Oh, no!
اوه, نه
Oh, God!
اوه, خداي من
Hey, man, you just fucked up your Ferrari.
هي,مرد,تو ند زدي به اون ماشين فراري
- Oh, no! Baby's goin' down in flames! - It's not mine.
اوه, نه اون ماشين رفت توي دل آتيش اون مال من نيست
Neither is this!
اينم همينطور
Damn! This sucks! Where's that son of a bitch at?
لعنتي!لعنتي اون مردتيكه عوضي كجاست؟
I'm gonna hunt him down! That motherfucker ain't safe nowhere.
من اونو شكارش ميكنم! اون عوضي نميتونه جايي بره
- Chem weapons. Isherwood. - Marvin, look up Wolfburg Federal Penitentiary.
بخش سلاحهاي شيميايي. ايشر وود هستم ماروين, يه ناهي به بازداشتاه فدرال ولفبور بكن
The inmate is Mason, John.
يه زنداني به اسم جان ميسون
Hey, Stan, listen, I'm gettin' out of this government shithole.
هي, استن, وش كن,من دارم از كار دولتي خارج ميشم
I'm goin' over to Orkin to design roach motels. Cool, huh?
ميخوام برم به اوركين تا موتل طراحي كنم. جالبه,ها؟
Look, I just stole a kid's motorcycle.
ببين, من الان موتورسيكلت يه به رو دزديم
I'm not really feeling too good about it, okay? Wolfburg. Got it?
اصلا هم احساس خوبي نسبت به اين قضيه ندارم, باشه؟ ولفبور.يداش كردي؟
Yeah, I got it. All right, Magrane, Masconi, Masters. No Mason.
آره,يداش كردم. خب بزار ببينم مارانه, ماسكني, مسترز.ميسون وجود نداره
Go to February '76. Who was transferred to Wolfburg from San Quentin?
برو فوريه سال 76 رو ك كن ببين ه كسي از سان كوئنتين به ولفبور منتقل شده؟
This is weird. They got medical records.
واقعا عجيبه توي اونها رونده هاي زشكي هستش
They got place of birth. Glasgow. Uh, but they don't have a name.
توي اونها محل تولد هستش. جدول لاسكو آه, اما اونها اسم ندارن
Uh, wait a minute, wait a minute. They have next of kin.
آه, يه لحظه صبر كن, يه لحظه صبر كن اسم بستان درجه يك هستش
A Jade Angelou of 32 Stenson Drive, San Francisco.
يه اسم به نام جيد آنجلو خيابان اسنسون, شماره 32,سان فرانسيسكو
Jade?
جيد؟
No, Stacy. Jade's friend.
نه, استيسي هستم.دوست جيد
Were you afraid to come alone?
ميترسيدي كه تنها بياي؟
Yeah.
آره
- It's okay. - I'll be over here if you need me.
مشكلي نيست اه بهم احتياج داشتي من همين اطرافم
The last photograph I had of you, you were about ten.
آخرين عكسي كه ازت داشتم,تو حدودا 10 سالت بود
Yeah?
راستي؟
Well, I found a picture of you among my mom's things when she died.
خب,وقتي مادرم مرد يه عكس از شما توي خرت و رتهاي مادرم يدا كردم
Oh, yeah? Well, uh... Why don't we take a walk?
...اوه, راستي؟ خب,اه راه بريم و صحبت كنيم
I got 'im. Palace of Fine Arts.
ديدمش كاخ هنرهاي زيبا
Your mother, uh... Yeah, well, sh-she was very special.
مادرت, آه... آره, خب اون-اون آدم خيلي خاصي بود
Yeah, she was.
آره, همينطوره
But I don't think that we should romanticize what happened between you and her.
اما من فكر نميكنم ما بايد درباره آنه كه بين شما و اون اتفاق افتاد داستان سرايي كنيم
Meeting in a bar after a Led Zeppelin concert.
يه ملاقات توي ميكده بعد از كنسرت لد زلين
Head out, and I was the result.
و نتيجش هم من بودم
Well, I'd like to think it would've led somewhere if only...
خب, من ميخوام به آن فكر كنم ...ميتونست منجر به جايي بشه اه فقط
If only what? Six federal marshals hadn't kicked down our door...
اه فقط ي؟ اينكه 6 تا افسر ارشد فدرال ...اشنه در خونه رو از جا نميكندن
and dragged you back to prison?
و تو رو به زندون برنميردوندن؟
- I'm sorry. - It's all right.
متاسفم بذريم
- So, they let you out? - Yeah.
س اونا ذاشتن بياي بيرون؟ آره
That's good.
خوبه
What did you do?
يكار ميكردي؟
J...
...ج
Jade, I don't have a great deal of time here.
جيد, من خيلي وقت ندارم
But I'll be coming back. And, uh...
اما من برميردم ...و, آه
- Maybe we can... - What? We can what?
...شايد ما بتونيم ي؟ بتونيم يكار كنيم؟
You know, you're almost the only evidence...
...ميدوني,تو تقريبا تنها سندي هستي
that I exist.
كه من دارم
But I don't know you.
اما من تو رو نميشناسم
That's what I want to change, eh?
بهمين خاطره كه ميخوام عوض بشم,اه؟
I've rehearsed this speech a thousand times on the chance that we would meet.
من هزاران بار تمرين كردم تا اه شانس ديدن همديه رو داشتيم بتونم بيان كنم
Here we are, and I'm lost.
ما اينجائيم و من شكست خوردم
Well, I don't know how I'm supposed to be feeling either.
خب,من نميدونم ه احساسي بايد داشته باشم
Jade, I'm not an evil man.
جيد, من يه مرد شيطاني نيستم
If you can believe that, then it's a start.
اه بتوني اينو باور كني اين خودش يه نقطه شروعه
Okay.
باشه
Is this about you?
اينا دنبال تو اومدن؟
You broke out of prison again, didn't you? Why did you come to me?
تو دوباره از زندان فرار كردي,مه نه؟ را اومدي سراغ من؟
FBl, ma'am. Your father's working with us.
اف بي آي, خانم درتون دارن با ما همكاري ميكنن
He's helping us resolve a dangerous situation.
ايشون دارن به ما كمك ميكنن تا يه وضعيت خطرناك رو حل كنيم
- He is? - Yes, ma'am.
واقعا؟ بله, خانم
Well, gee whiz, John, I guess we oughta get goin', huh?
خب, جا, فكر ميكنم وقت رفتنه,ها؟
Whatever you say, Stanley.
هري تو بي, استنلي
Thank you for that. You could've handled it differently.
بخاطر اينكار ازت ممنونم نميتونستي يجور ديه اينكار رو انجام بدي؟
What do you say we cut the chitchat, a-hole?
ميخواي بي كه ما حرفتون رو قطع كرديم,الاغ؟
You almost got me killed twice. And my jaw hurts like hell!
نزديك بود 2 بار منو به كشتن بدي و فكم اومد ايين
- Good. - Cocksucker!
خوبه عوضي
If I had my way, you would be shipped back to Wolfburg in leg irons...
...اه دست من بود, برت ميردوندم به زندان ولفبور
and caged like an animal for the rest of your natural fucking life!
و مينداختمت توي قفس حيوانات تا زندي لعنتيت رو توي اون بذروني
You wrecked half the city!
تو نصف شهر رو بهم ريختي
Now, tell me about the tunnels.
حالا,درباره تونلها بهم بو
If you know the system, it will take you wherever you need to go.
اه شما اين سيستم رو بشناسيد هرجايي كه بخوايد شما رو ميبره
All right, there's an intake pipe here, below low tide. Is that our best access?
بسيار خب, اينجا يه لوله كم فشار وجود داره اين بهترين راه دسترسي ماست؟
Yes. That's exactly where I had come out.
آره.اين دقيقا همون جائي هستش كه من ازش خارج شدم
Then beneath the cistern, there's a connection to the abandoned septic system.
بعدش زير آب انبار,يه راه ارتباطي با تصفيه خونه ي قديمي هستش
How many feet is that?
فاصلش قدره؟
Uh, 57 paces.
آه, 57 قدم
Where do we go from there?
از كجا ميتونيم بريم اونجا؟
That's a good question.
سوال خوبيه
- I have no idea. - What?
نظري ندارم ي؟
I mean, I'll know it when we're all inside.
منظورم اينه كه, وقتي هممون بريم داخل ميفهمم
No. You're not goddam goin'. Show us on the blueprints.
نه. تو نميري اون تو نقشه رو نشونمون بده
I can't! My blueprint was in my head.
نميتونم اينكار رو بكنم نقشه من توي ذهنم بود
I was underground for three days in the dark,
من براي 3 روز توي تاريكي اون زير بودم
just waiting for the tides to be right.
فقط بايد صبر كنيم تا جزر و مد انجام بشه
But don't worry. It'll all come back to me.
اما نران نباشيد همش به من برميرده
You're not going anywhere, Mason.
تو هيجا نميري,ميسون
Wait a second. Now, this piece of work might be the only chance those people over there have.
يه لحظه صبر كن اين بخش از كار ممكنه تنها راه رسيدن ما به اون آدمها باشه
If he's not going, then why the hell did we get him out of jail?
اه اون نره, س براي ي از زندان آورديمش بيرون؟
- He's smart. - I got him out to get you people in, not go with you.
اون آدم باهوشيه من اين آدم رو آوردم بيرون تا شما را ببره داخل, نه اينكه با شما بره داخل
If it's the only way of getting the intelligence I need, then he goes.
اه اينكار تنها راه دستيابي به اطلاعات مورد نياز باشه,اونم مياد
He'll fuck with you.
اون همتون رو به ا ميده
You compromise my men's lives, and I'll bury you out there.
اه جون آدماي منو بخطر بندازي,همونجا خاكت ميكنم
Now, Womack,
حالا, ووماك
you're between The Rock and a hard case.
تو بين "راك" و قسمت مشكل داستان قرار داري
How is your bowling arm?
دستت طوره؟
Dr Goodspeed, the goal is to take out the launchers,
دكتر وود اسيد, هدف خارج كردن موشكها
then neutralize the V.X. chemical rounds.
و سس خنثي كردن كلاهكهاي شيميايي وي ايكس هستش
Well, we know the poison's being kept in the prison morgue from the satellite thermal imaging...
خب,ما ميدونيم مواد سمي در جايي از زندان نهداري ميشن كه تصوير برداري رمايي توسط ماهواره امكان ذير نباشه
which is right here; these colourized dots.
كه دقيقا اينجا هستن توي اين نقطه هاي رن شده
- Have you ever actually seen one of these devices? - No, sir, but I've studied them.
آيا شما تاحالا بطور واقعي هيكدوم از اين تجهيزات رو ديديد؟ خير, قربان, اما دربارشون مطالعه كردم
I should really begin briefing your guys on defusing and detoxification.
من بايد نيروهاي شما را درباره خنثي سازي و مسموميت زدايي توجيه كنم
Got a really neat layout over here of the chem round as well as the rocket,
يه راكت همراه با كلاهك شيميايي تميز آماده كنيد
- so let's get rolling. - That won't be necessary.
خب شروع كنيد اينكار لازم نيست
Oh, it's very necessary, sir.
اوه, خيلي هم لازمه,قربان
The power of this chemical is way beyond anything you can imagine.
قدرت اين ماده شيميايي فراتر از اون يزيه كه بتونيد تصور كنيد
An ecological disaster, sir.
يه فاجعه زيست محيطي,قربان
Plus the devices themselves are complicated.
بعلاوه كه خود تجهيزات هم ييده هستن
That's why you're coming with us.
براي همينه كه شما با ما ميائيد
- I am? - You're the expert. What's your problem?
من؟ شما يه فرد متخصص هستيد مشكلي داريد؟
You mean I'm going, going out there, under the water?
منظورتون اينه كه بيام, بيام اونجا, زير آب؟
Well, earlier today you wanted a gun.
خب, توامروز اول صبح يه اسلحه خواستي
Now you're getting a gun and a wet suit.
حالا يه اسحه و يه لباس غواصي مييري
Have you ever been in a combat situation?
تا حالا توي يه موقعيت جني بودي؟
- Define "combat," sir. - Shep?
موقعيت جني رو تعريف كنيد,قربان ش؟
An incursion underwater to retake an impregnable fortress held by an elite team...
يك حمله زيرآبي جهت بازس يري يك سنر غيرقابل نفوذ ...كه توسط يك تيم زبده
of U.S. Marines in possession of 81 hostages and 15 guided rockets...
از تفنداران دريايي آمريكا محافظت ميشه ...جهت تصرف 81 روان و 15 موشك
armed with V.X. poisoned gas.
مسلح به از سمي وي ايكس
Oh. In that case, no, sir. Excuse me.
اوه.در اين مورد, خير, قربان ببخشيد
- Here. - Ah, thank you.
بيرش اه, ممنون
You don't look too good.
خيلي سرحال بنظر نميرسي
In fact, you look like shit.
راستش بنظر مياد ريدي به خودت
My stomach's doing hula hoops around my ass.
شكمم داره دور باسنم ي ميخوره
You all right?
حالت خوبه؟
I mean, you gonna make it through this thing?
منظورم اينه كه, اينجوري ميخواي انجامش بدي؟
I don't know.
نميدونم
I always expected something like this was going to happen,
من هميشه انتظار هر اتفاقي رو دارم
but nothing prepares you for it.
اما آماده اين يزي كه شما مييد نيستم
Now I'm... I'm responsible...
...توي اين شرايط من ...من مسول
for a whole city.
جون افراد يك شهر هستم
Look, I know this isn't easy for you.
ببين, ميدونم كه اين قضيه برات آسون نيست
Remember you were trained for this kind of a situation...
...يادت باشه كه تو براي همين موقعيتهايي آموزش ديدي
and believe me, it'll come back to you.
و باور كن,منم به شما ملحق ميشم
Besides, you got the best SEAL team in the country backing you up.
ذشته از اينها, تو بهترين تيم رزمي كشور رو در كنارت داري
Okay. You're right.
بسيارخب حق با شماست
l-I'll be on the wire. I'll help talk you through it.
من-من شت خط ميمونم كمكت ميكنم كه از آن طريق صحبت كني
There's something else.
يه يز ديه هم هست
It's terrible. N-No, it's wonderful,
اون وحشتناكه ن-نه, اون عجيبه
except it isn't.
انتظار اونو نداشتم
My girlfriend's pregnant...
...دوست دخترم بارداره
and she's just flown in to see me.
و داره مياد كه منو ببينه
You keep your mind on what you're going to be doing out there tonight.
حواست رو بده به كاري كه امشب ميخواي انجام بدي
And I'll send someone to pick up your girlfriend and bring her here to the command centre.
و منم يه نفر ميفرستم دوست دخترت رو بياره اينجا به مركز فرماندهي
- Hummel! - Hello, Frank. Lou Linstrom.
هومل سلام, فرانك. لو لينستورم هستم
I'm at the White House with General Kramer.
من همراه با ژنرال كريمر در كاخ سفيد هستم
Uh, Frank, uh, we're havin' a few problems with the account transfer.
آه, فرانك, آه ما درباره انتقال ول به ندتا مشكل برخورديم
- Don't tell me problems, tell me solutions. - Now, we've spoken to the president,
درباره مشكلات باهام حرف نزن درباره راهكارها بو الان, با رئيس جمهور صحبت كرديم
and I know that you're well aware of his stance on terrorism.
و ميدونم كه تو بخوبي از مواضع ضد تروريستي اون آاهي
- So what we'd like to do is... - This isn't about terrorism. This is about justice.
...خب كاري كه ما ميخوايم بكنيم اينه كه اين قضيه ربطي به تروريسم نداره اين قضيه مربوط به عدالته
It's about reminding you people who found it politically convenient to forget.
It's about reminding you people who found it politically convenient to forget.
This is goin' nowhere, Frank.
اين قضيه هي جا درز نميكنه فرانك
Well, then, let me tell you what is.
خب, س,س بذار بهت بم داستان يه
Fifteen V.X. gas rockets into the heart of San Francisco.
ونزده موشك مسلح به از وي ايكس به سمت قلب سان فرانسيسكو نشونه رفته
You've got 17 hours to deliver the money.
شما 17 ساعت براي تحويل ول فرصت داريد
Or be prepared to reap the whirlwind, gentlemen.
يا آماده طوفان باشيد, آقايون
- What's the word from Mojave? - General Peterson can give us...
از موجاوه ه خبر؟ ...طبق فته ژنرال ترسون
no definite assurance on the thermite plasma.
هي اطمينان قطعي در مورد لاسماي ترميت وجود نداره
That is the word.
اينم از اين
Green light to SEAL incursion.
بيد عمليات رو شروع كنن
Fall in! All right, listen up.
به خط بشيد بسيارخب, وش كنيد
Mr Mason will run point for us.
آقاي ميسون راهنماي ما هستن
Lieutenant Shepard will be attached to his hip.
ستوان شيارد به ايشون ملحق خواهند شد
You breathe, he breathes with you. You piss, he helps.
وقتي نفس بکشيد,اونم با شما نفس ميکشه وقتي بشاشيد, اون کمک ميکنه
Understood?
متوجه شديد؟
Dr Goodspeed is our specialist.
دكتر وود اسيد متخصص ما هستند
When he neutralizes the threat, we launch green flares and we wait for the cavalry.
وقتي اون تهديد رو خنثي ميكنه ما منور سبز شليك ميكنيم و منتظر نيروي زرهي ميشيم
Make no mistake, gentlemen. We're in the fight of our lives...
هي اشتباهي مرتكب نشيد, آقايون ...ما داريم جونمون رو ميذاريم
against maybe the greatest battalion commander in the Vietnam War.
تا شايد با بزرترين فرماندهي در جن ويتنام بجنيم
I shit you not.
خراب كاري نكنيد
Any questions?
سوالي هست؟
Let's load up!
سوارشيد
After you, ace.
اول شما, قهرمان
Pass out and activate the minicams.
دوربينهاتون رو فعال كنيد
Everything set here? Minicams operational?
همه ي مرتبه؟ دوربينهاي كويك فعال هستند؟
Roger that, sir. We are on-line.
دريافت شد, قربان ما روي خط هستيم
Shep, what's the status on the special operational gear for Mr Mason?
ش, وضعيت تجهيزات عملياتي مخصوص آقاي ميسون طوره؟
Uh, let's see. We have, uh,
اوه, بزار ببينم ما اينجا,آه
one quart of kerosene in a squeeze bottle.
يه بطري نفت سفيد داريم
Three washers and waterproof matches.
سه تا واشر و كبريت ضد آب داريم
Use the green flares to signal when the threat has been neutralized.
وقتي تهديد خنثي شد با منور سبز علامت بديد
Now, this is atropine. If you come in contact with the gas,
اينهم آتروينه. اه با از تماس يدا كرديد
you have 20 seconds to inject it into your heart.
شما 20 ثانيه فرصت داريد تا اونو به داخل قلبتون تزريق كنيد
Don't fuck with me on this. It may save your life.
اينجوري نيام نكنيد اون ممكنه جونتون رو نجات بده
I have three incoming bogeys bearing 275.
من 3 تا رنده ناشناس در جهت 275 ميبينم
Range: 6,000 metres.
محدوده: 6000 متر
FBl Command Centre?
مركز فرماندهي اف بي آي؟
- Oh, I would just love for you to tell me what is goin' on. - Nope.
اوه,ميخوام بهم بي اينجا ه خبره نه
Listen, Stanley Goodspeed is my boyfriend. Actually, he's, um, my fiance.
وش كن, استنلي وود اسيد دوست سر منه راستش, اون, ام,نامزد منه
- Where is he? - Classified, lady.
اون كجاست؟ محرمانست, خانم
Okay. Well, you just sit here and act like a Bureau bonehead, then.
خيلي خب.تو فقط اينجا بشين و مثل آدماي كله خر رفتار كن,باشه؟
Hey, where are you g... Goddam it!
...هي,شما كجا داريد مير لعنتي
Decoy choppers commencing run to Alcatraz.
هليكوترها دارن بسمت آلكاتراس ميان
I just lost one, sir. I just lost one.
يكيشون رو م كردم, قربان يكيشون رو م كردم
- We only got two flying in. - Shit!
ما فقط 2 تاشون رو داريم يكيشون رو م كرديم لعنتي
In my day, we did it all with a snorkel and a pair of flippers.
در روز من ما اونكار رو با يه لوله تنفسي و يه جفت باله شنا انجام داديم
- Your day? - Yes. Didn't you read my resume?
روز تو؟ آره. مه رزومه ي منو نخوندي؟
I don't... I don't know anything about you.
...نه من يزي درباره تو نميدونم
- Hmm. I know something about you, Godspell. - Goodspeed.
همم.من يه يزايي درباره تو ميدونم, وود اسل وود اسيد
Goodspeed, Godspeed, Godspell,
وود اسيد,وود اسيد وود اسل
you never went to any antiterrorist school.
تو هي وقت به مدرسه ضد تروريستي نرفتي
So just make sure you don't get us all fucking killed.
فقط مراقب باش همه ما رو به كشتن ندي
- We're goin' dark. - Night vision!
به حالت مخفي ميريم ديد در شب
Raider One has dropped below radar coverage,
مهاجم يك از تيررس رادار خارج شد
heading around Treasure Island.
مسير حركت بسمت جزيره نج
Sir, we've got two bogeys bearing due east and closing.
قربان, دوتا رنده ناشناس از سمت شرق دارن نزديك ميشن
Decoys?
رد م كنيه؟
- Prepare to deploy! - Good luck, Commander.
آماده انجام ماموريت موفق باشيد, فرمانده
Sir, Raider One is at the drop zone.
قربان,مهاجم يك داره فرود مياد
Stanley's not a very good swimmer. I mean, he can't even snorkel.
استنلي شنار خيلي خوبي نيست منظورم اينه كه, اون حتي غواصي هم نكرده
- Everyone, good to go? - Good to go!
همي, حاضريد؟ حاضريم
- Good to go! Good to go!
حاضريم! حاضريم
All right, so the S.D.U.s have been deployed, and the Eagles are in the water.
بسيارخب, خب اس دي يو ها مستقر شده ان و عقابها درون آب هستن
Major, I want the perimeter patrolled to the west end of the island.
قربان!شت دريايي بسمت انتهاي غربي جزيره رو ميخوام
- Double-time it. - Yes, sir. Hendrix!
زمانش رو دوبربر كنيد بله, قربان. هندريكس
- You lead the patrol. - Aye, aye, sir.
تو مسول شت زني هستي بله, بله, قربان
Let's move. Move out! Move out! Move out!
بريم. راه بيفتيد راه بيفتيد! راه بيفتيد
The Eagles are on The Rock. They've entered the cistern room.
عقابها وارد "راك" شدند اونها توي آب انبار هستن
Thank you very fucking much, Mr Mason.
بينهايت ازت ممنونم,آقاي ميسون
You've led us into a room with no exit.
تو ما رو وارد اتاقي كردي كه هي خروجي نداره
- Any ideas, Dillinger? - Figure it out soon. We're sitting ducks.
نظري نداري, ديلينر؟ بزودي راه خروج رو يدا ميكنيم We're sitting ducks.
We're a little tight on time.
ما فقط يه خورده كمبود وقت داريم
You stand by the door until I open it.
تا من در رو باز كنم شما آماده باشيد
I'd like to know how you plan on accomplishing that?
دوست دارم بدونم برنامت براي انجام اين كار يه؟
Through here.
از توي اينجا
- You're shitting me. - I memorized the timing.
منو دست ميندازي؟ مشكل زمان رو يادآوري ميكنم
I just hope it hasn't been changed.
فقط دعا ميكنم عوض نشده باشه
You catch one of those flame bursts, you're a corpse.
اه انفجاري صورت بيري,خودت هم مردي
- Thank you. - Commander, you said never to leave his sight, but, uh...
ممنون ..فرمانده, شما فتيد هي وقت شم ازش برنداريم, اما,آه
Stand fast, Lieutenant.
دست نه دار,لوتينانت
Have a nice day.
روز خوبي داشته باشيد
- Where'd you dig up this guy? - That's classified.
كجا رو فتيد اين رو بكنه؟ محرمانست
Clear here, sir. No motion sensors tripped.
اينجا امنه, قربان هي حركتي توسز حسرها ثبت نشده
- Nothing. - Well, tell 'em to stay out there.
هيي خب,بهشون بو همون اطراف بمونن
Sweep forward!
به يش
Looks like he fucked us, Commander.
بنظر مياد سرمون شيره ماليد,فرمانده
I knew it. That son of a bitch jumped ship.
ميدونستم اون عوضي زد به اك
Welcome to The Rock.
به "راك" خوش آمديد
- Mason. - That's a no-no.
ميسون اون هيي نيست
That's the subway. That'll drop you into the tunnels.
اون راه زيرزمينيه. اون شما رو به سمت تونلها ميبره
Do it!
برش دار
Sir, the Eagles have breached the tunnel system.
قربان, عقابها به داخل سيستم تونلها نفوذ كردن
You enjoying this?
از اين خوشت مياد؟
Well, it's certainly more enjoyable than my average day.
خب,اون مخصوصا لذت بخشتر از متوسط روز منه
Reading philosophy, avoiding gang rape in the washroom.
خوندن فلسفه,مانع از تجاوز جنايتكارانه در حمام ميشه
Though it's less of a problem these days. Maybe I'm losing my sex appeal.
اره اين روزها اين قضيه كمتر مشكل شده شايدم من دارم جذبه جنسيم رو ازدست ميدم
We've got seismic activity in one of the storm grates. North side.
ما يكسري فعاليتهاي لرزشي در يكي از شبكه ها ثبت كرديم سمت شمال
Continue patrolling the area.
به شت زني در اون محدوده ادامه بديد
Sweep forward!
به يش
Commander, halt. We've got movement.
فرمانده, صبر كنيد صداي حركت ميشنويم
- They're hearing sounds above, sir. - Stand fast.
اونها بالاي سرشون صداهايي ميشنون, قربان دست نه داريد
Down, down, down.
بريد ايين, بريد ايين, بريد ايين
West storm drain's clear.
آبذر غربي امنه
Ninety-seven paces to the shower room.
نود و هفت قدم تا اتاق دوش مونده
The Eagles are now at the access tunnel. They're right under the shower room, sir.
عقابها الان در تونل ورودي هستن اونها درست زير اتاق دوش هستند,قربان
Fibre optics.
فيبر نوري
- Something's not right. - I got a bad feeling about this.
يه يزي درست نيست من يه حس بدي بهش دارم
Quiet.
ساكت
Motion sensors.
حسرهاي حركتي
- Beams cutting across the manhole covers. - Deal with it.
رتوها از ميان وششهاي مدور رد ميشن باهاش سروكار داشتم
Commander, the beam is hitting some sort of reflective device.
فرمانده,اين رتو داره به يجور دستاه انعكاسي برخورد ميكنه
Possibly a prism.
احتمالا به يه منشور
I want to use a mirror to cut the beam,
ميخوام با استفاده از آينه مسير رتو رو قطع كنم
send the beam back to its source and then I'm gonna move the prism.
رتو رو به منبعش برميردونم و بعدش منشور رو برميدارم
We've got motion on a trembler in the shower room, sir.
يه حركت لرزشي در اتاق دوش داريم,قربان
We've got visitors. Let's move.
نتا ملاقاتي داريم بريم
Got it. Good to go.
انجام شد حاضريم
- Fuck, man! I knew this would happen! Fuck! - Move!
لعنتي!ميدونستم اين اتفاق ميوفته! لعنتي بريم
Stand fast. We'll secure the area.
صبر كنيد ما منطقه رو امن ميكنيم
They're entering into the shower room, sir.
اونها دارن وارد اتاق دوش ميشن, قربان
They're securing the area.
اونها دارن منطقه رو امن ميكنن
Just sit tight.
فقط سفت بير بشين
Drop your weapons! Drop 'em!
اسلحه هاتون رو بندازيد بندازيدشون
- Stand fast! - Hold your fire!
دست نهداريد شليک نکنيد
- Drop your weapons!
اسلحه هاتون رو بندازيد
It's a fucking trap.
اين يه تلست
This is General Hummel.
ژنرال هامل هستم
Drop your weapons. Drop 'em!
اسلحه هاتون رو بندازيد بندازيدشون
Anderson here, General Hummel.
اندرسون هستم ژنرال هامل
Commander. Team leader.
فرمانده. سردسته ي تيم
Commander Anderson, if you have any concern for the lives of your men,
...فرمانده اندرسون, اه ج.ن افرادت برات مهمه
you will order them to safety their weapons and place them on the deck.
بهشون دستور بده اسلحه هاشون رو به آرومي بذارن زمين
This is not happening.
اين اتفاق نبايد بيفته
Sir, we know why you're out here.
قربان,ما ميدونيم شما براي ي اينجا هستيد
God knows I agree with you.
خدا شاهده كه من با شما موافق هستم
But like you, I swore to defend this country against all enemies,
اما مثل شما,قسم خوردم كه از اين كشور در برابر تمام دشمنان دفاع كنم
foreign, sir, and domestic.
دشمنان خارجي,قربان و دشمنان داخلي
General, we've spilled the same blood in the same mud.
ژنرال,ما هم قسم شده ايم
You know goddam well I can't give that order.
شما خوب ميدونيد كه نميتونم همين دستوري بدم
We're dead.
ما مرديم
Your unit is covered from an elevated position, Commander.
واحد شما از بالا تحت وششه, فرمانده
I'm not gonna ask you again. Don't do anything stupid.
قصد ندارم دوباره درخواستم رو تكرار كنم كار احمقانه اي انجام نده
No one has to die here.
هي كسي اينجا كشته نميشه
Men following the General, you're under oath as United States Marines!
نيروهاي ژنرال!شما بعنوان تفداران دريايي آمريكا سوند خورده ايد
Have you forgotten that?
يادتون رفته؟
We all have shipmates we remember.
ما همي هم خدمت هم هستيم
Some of them were shit on and pissed on by the Pentagon.
نتاون بعضي ها رو رنجوند و به لجن كشيد
- But that doesn't give you the right to mutiny! - You call it what you want!
اما اين قضيه به شما اين حق رو نميده كه شورش كنيد شما هري ميخواي اسمش رو بذار
You're down there, we're up here. You walked into the wrong goddam room, Commander!
شما اين ايين هستيم, ما هم اين بالا. شما هم وارد يه اتاق اشتباهي شديد, فرمانده
- Stand fast! - Goddam it, Commander, one last time.
دست نه داريد لعنت, فرمانده, براي آخرين بار
You tell your men to safety their weapons, drop 'em on the deck.
به افرادن بو آروم اسلحه هاشون رو بذارن زمين
- I cannot give that order! - I am not gonna repeat that order!
نميتونم همين دستوري بدم نميخوام دستورم رو دوباره تكرار كنم
- I will not give that order! - What the hell is wrong with you, man?
من همين دستوري نميدم ه مرت شده, مرد؟
- Stand fast! - Oh, my God!
صبر كنيد اوه, خداي من
- Let's waste these fuckers. - One last time. You order your men to safety their weapons...
بذار دخل اين عوضي ها رو بياريم ..براي آخرين بار.به افرادت دستور بده تا آروم اسلحه هاشون رو
Cease fire!
تيراندازي نكنيد
Don't go.
نرو
Shit! Goddam it!
لعنتي! لعنتي
Let go of me. Let go of me!
بذار برم
Don't. Don't go.
نه. نرو
It's over.
تموم شد
Oh, God!
اوه,خداي من
Later.
عقبي
- We got some movement. - Who? - Two of 'em!
ند تا حركت داريم كي؟ دو تا از اونها
- Who is it? - Eagles 11 and 12.
كيه؟ عقاب 11 و 12
- l-lt's Goodspeed and Mason. - I knew it.
اون-اون وود اسيد و ميسونه ميدونستم
I've gotta get a team together right now. We've gotta move with the second option.
من يه تيم ميخوام. ما بايد بريم روي طرح دوم
What, and invite another massacre? No way.
ي؟يه كشتار ديه ميخواي راه بندازي؟ هي راهي نيست
We've got a 60-year-old convict and a lab rat. I'm telling you, it's over.
ما يه مجرم 60 ساله و يه موش آزمايشاهي داريم دارم بهت ميم,اونا شكست خوردن
Not for Mason, it isn't.
نه براي ميسون اون شكست نميخوره
Goodspeed, I'm not gonna kill you.
وود ايد من نميخوام بكشمت
- Where are you going? - Off this bloody island.
كجا داري ميري؟ از اين جزيره خونخوار خارج ميشم
What? Wh-Wh-What for?
ي؟ --براي ي؟
Goodspeed. Goodspeed, do you read me?
وود اسيد وود اسيد,صدام رو ميشنوي؟
It's for you.
با تو كار دارن
- Sir? - What's the status?
قربان؟ اعلام وضعيت؟
The status is they're dead. They're dead!
وضعيت اينه كه اونا مردن اونا مردن
It's just me and Mason. Now he says he's leaving.
الان فقط من و ميسون هستيم اون الان فت كه داره از اينجا ميره
That is unacceptable. Do you hear me? Unacceptable!
غير قابل قبوله فهميدي؟ غير قابل قبوله
Well, there's a problem, sir. He's got a gun.
خب,يه مشكلي وجود داره, قربان اون يه اسلحه داره
What do you have, a fuckin' water pistol?
ي داري,يه تفن آب باش؟
- No, sir. - Go after him and stop him.
نه,قربان دنبالش برو و جلوش رو بير
I didn't want this.
من اينو نميخواستم
- Jesus, I didn't want this. - You knew this might happen, Frank.
خداي من,من اينو نميخواستم ميدونستي كه اين اتفاق ممكنه بيوفته, فرانك
- Well, maybe now they'll pay up. - Maybe now they won't, Captain.
خب, ممكن بود اونا حساب ما رو برسن حالا كه اينكار رو نكردن, كايتان
Then maybe we need to execute a few hostages.
س شايد لازم باشه ند تا از روانها رو بكشيم
- Got a live one! - Put a bullet in him.
يكيشون زندست يه لوله بهش بزن
- You heard him. End it! - Holster that sidearm, Captain.
شنيدي. خلاصش كن اسلحت رو غلاف كن, كايتان
Sir?
قربان؟
You made a terrible mistake.
اشتباه بزري مرتكب شدي
And more of our brothers have died in vain.
بيشتر برادرهاي ما به خاطر هي مردن
Damn you for forcing me into this position.
لعنت به تو كه منو توي اين موقعيت قرار دادي
I need to talk to you right now, alone.
بايد همين الان باهات حرف بزنم, تنها
Now you told me I'm on a need-to-know basis.
الان بهم فتي من فقط موارد ايه اي رو بايد بدونم
And I'm tellin' you right now, I need to know who the fuck John Mason is right now, sir.
و منم الان بهت ميم من بايد بدونم اين ميسون لعنتي كيه, قربان
All right, you wanna know? 1962, J. Edgar Hoover...
بسيار خب, ميخواي بدوني؟ ...سال 1962, جي ادار هوفر
is head of the FBl, some say the country.
رئيس اف بي آي يه يزايي درباره کشور ميه
It's no secret he kept microfilm files on prominent Americans and Europeans:
اون رونده افراد مهم آمريکايي و اروايي رو :روي يک ميکروفيلم نهداري ميکنه
de Gaulle, British members of Parliament, even the Prime Minister.
دوئلا, اعضاي  ارلمان انليس, و حتي نخست وزير
I mean, this guy had dirt on everybody in the world.
منظورم اينه که, اين يارو براي هرکسي توي دنيا يه رونده داشت
Yeah, I know all the cloak-and-dagger stories. Where does Mason fit in?
آره, من همه اين داستان دزد و ليس رو ميدونم ميسون اين وسط يکارست؟
Mason was the British operative who stole the files.
ميسون مامور انليسهاست که اين رونده ها رو ميدزده
But our Bureau agents caught him at the Canadian border.
اما مامورهاي ما اونو توي مرز کانادا دستير ميکنن
Of course, the British claimed they'd never heard of him.
البته, دولت انليس ادعا ميکنه هرز يزي درباره ميسون نشنيده
And we held him without trial...
...و ما اونو بدون اينکه محاکمه کنيم نه ميداريم
until he gave up the microfilm, but he never did.
تا شايد اون ميکروفيلم رو بهمون بده اما اون هرز اينکار رو نکرد
Well, I'm surprised Hoover didn't use his daughter as leverage.
خب, تعجب ميکنم از اينکه هوفر از دخترش بعنوان اهرم استفاده نکرد
Hoover was dead in '72. She wasn't born yet.
هوفر در سال 1972 فوت کرد اون موقع دختره هنوز متولد نشده بود
Today, well, it's a different Bureau.
امروز, خب, مسول فرد ديه ايه
So you held this guy without trial his whole life! No wonder he's pissed.
شما تمام اين مدت اونو بدون محاکمه نهداشتيد تعجب نميکنم که اون اينقدر ناراحته
This man knows our most intimate secrets from the last half century:
:اين مرد بيشتر اسرار محرمانه ما رو از نيم قرن ذشته ميدونه
the alien landing at Roswell, the truth about the J.F.K. assassination.
فرود بيانه در فروداه روزولت, حقيقت ترور جي اف کندي
And Mason's angry, he's lethal, he's a trained killer.
و ميسون عصابنيه,اون مخربه اون يه قاتل آموزش ديدست
And he is the only hope that we have got.
و اون تنها اميديه که ما داريم
Mason! Mason!
ميسون! ميسون
There are 81 hostages still up there.
هنوز 81 روان اون بالا هستش
Yeah, like me.
آره, درست مثل من
All right, you wanna play tough? You wanna play tough with me?
بسيارخب, ميخواي خشن بازي کني؟ ميخواي با من خشن بازي کني؟
Okay. FBl! Freeze, sucker!
بسيارخب.اف بي آي تکون نخور, احمق
- I'll fire. - No, you won't.
شليک ميکنم نه, اينکار رو نميکني
- Throw down. - You're not the sort.
دراز بکش تو مال اين حرفا نيستي
Let's find out.
ميخواي تست کنيم؟
I could; you, no.
من ميتونم; اما تو نه
Besides, your safety's on.
بعلاوه,ضامن رو نکشيدي
Goodspeed, have you resolved the situation?
وود اسيد, آيا مشکل رو حل کردي؟
Not yet.
هنوز نه
- He's got all the guns now, sir. - Shit!
اون الان اسلحم رو رفت, قربان لعنتي
You're right, I don't use guns and I don't kick down doors.
تو راست ميي,من اسلحه دستم نرفتم حتي نميتونم به در لد بزنم
- This is what I do. - I haven't got my glasses.
اين کاريه که من ميتونم بکنم عينکم همرام نيست
What it says is Chemical Weapons Specialist.
اين ميه که من متخصص سلاحهاي شيميايي هستم
That's right. I got a lunatic up there, man,
درسته من بايد ديوونه باشم که بيام اينجا,مرد
with 15 missiles armed with some really funky stuff.
با 15 موشک مسلح همراه با ند نفر آدم ند دماغ
That lying Womack. You could've told my daughter.
اي ووماک دروغو شايد به دخترم فته باشي
It was classified. Look, I'm in the same situation.
اين يه موضوع محرمانست ببين, منم توي يه موقعيتي مثل تو هستم
They've got my girlfriend in the city with a baby on the way.
اونها دوست دخترم رو که حامله هم هست رفتن
Look, I can defuse the rockets. I really can.
ببين, من ميتونم اون راکتها رو خنثي کنم واقعا ميتونم اينکار رو بکنم
But I'm gonna need your help, and I'm gonna need it right now.
اما به کمکت احتياج دارم و همين الانم به کمکت نياز دارم
Sir, this man's weapons and tack radio are missing!
قربان, سلاح اين فرد و بيسيمش نيستش
Shit, we got a rodent problem. Flush the pipes.
لعنتي, ما يه جانور داريم لوله ها روبرديد
There's probably a maze of tunnels on this goddam island. Check every access you can find.
احتمالا بايد تونلهاي ي دري توي اين جزيره لعنتي باشه همه جار رو برديد
Sir.
بله قربان
Even if you escape from the island,
حتي ار بتوني از جزيره فرار کني
you can't escape the rockets.
از اون راکتها نميتوني فرار کني
So, where are you gonna go? Go where? What are, what are you gonna do?
خب, کجا ميخواي بري؟ کجا؟ يکار, يکار ميخواي بکني؟
- Show me where the morgue is, Mason. - I'm out of here.
سردخونه رو بهم نشون بده, ميسون من نيستم
What about your daughter? Mason?
دخترت ي ميشه؟ ميسون؟
Rodents located.
محلشون شناسايي شد
The way I see it, you don't really have any choice, do you?
من اين راه رو ميبينم, تو انتخاب ديه اي نداري, داري؟
I don't think you do.
من مثل تو فکر نميکنم
Move!
برو
They're onto us.
اونها بالاي سرما هستن
Burn 'em out.
بسوزونيدشون
This mother's gonna blow big.
اينهم يه انفجار درست و حسابي
I don't understand. How could we lose radio contact all of a sudden?
نميفهمم.طور تمام تماسهاي راديوييمون رو يه دفعه ازدست داديم؟
We've lost coms. Still got 'em on locaters.
سينالها رو ازدست داديم ولي همنان روي ردياب داريمشون
- So what's it gonna be? - What?
خي يکار ميخواي بکني؟ يرو؟
How do you like your choices?
دوست داري انتخابت ي باشه؟
- I don't. - That's what I thought.
نميدونم اون يزيه که من فکر ميکنم
All right, come on.
بسيارخب, راه بيفت
This is the oldest part of Alcatraz.
اينجا قديمي ترين قسمت آلکاتراس هستش
Did you know it was originally a Civil War fort?
ميدونستي اون اساسا قلعه جن داخلي بود؟
Oh, really? Huh. Yeah, wow. You know, I like history, too,
اوه, واقعا؟ هاه. آره, واو ميدوني,من تاريخ رو هم دوست دارم
maybe when this is all over, you and l can stop by the souvenir shop together.
شايد وقتي همه اينها تموم بشه,منو تو رو باهم به عنوان يادبود توي مغازه بذارن
But right now I just... I just... I wanna find some rockets.
اما الان فقط ميخوام... فقط ميخوام... ميخوام اون راکتها رو يدا کنم
Don't tempt me. We are going to the morgue.
منو ول نزن ما ميخوايم بريم به سردخونه
- You sure you're ready for this? - I'll do my best.
تو واقعا آمادي اينکار رو داري؟ تمام تلاشم رو ميکنم
Your best?
تمام تلاشت رو؟
Losers always whine about their best.
بازنده ها هميشه درباره تمام تلاششون حرف ميزنن
Winners go home and fuck the prom queen.
برنده ها ميرن خونه و دهن وزير رقاصه رو سرويس ميکنن
Carla was the prom queen.
کارلا وزيررقاصه بود
- Really? - Yeah.
واقعا؟ آره
Locaters have them approaching the morgue, sir.
رديابها نشون ميدن که اونها نزديک سردخونه هستند,قربان
Come on, come on. You can do it, Doc.
يالا, يالا تو ميتوني اينکار رو بکني, دکتر
You must never hesitate.
هي وقت نبايد ترديد کني
I think you're shooting too close to the rocket.
فکر ميکنم داري خيلي نزديک به راکتها شليک ميکني
Him, but not the rocket.
اونو بزن, نه راکتها رو
Any other news, Professor?
مطلب ديه اي نست,روفسور؟
Not the rocket! Not the rocket.
به راکتها نزن
I got a little somethin' for ya.
يه يز کوولو براتون دارم
Oh, yeah, okay. That's just about the most awful thing I've ever seen.
اوه, آره. اين ترسناک ترين يزي بود که تا حالا ديده بودم
Mason,
ميسون
the second you don't respect this, it kills you.
اه بهش احترام نذاري,تو رو ميکشه
Put it over there.
بذارش اونجا
You've been around a lot of corpses. Is that normal?
اطرافت جسدهاي زيادي هست. اين طبيعيه؟
- What, the feet thing? - Yeah, the feet thing.
يه, اش ميلرزه؟ آره, اش داره ميلرزه
- Yeah, that happens. - Well, I'm having kind of a hard time concentrating.
آره, ميتونه اتفاق بيوفته خب, من ميخوام شديدا تمرکز کنم
- Can you do something about it? - Well, like what? Kill him again?
ميتوني اونو يه کاريش کني؟ خب, مثلا يکارش کنم؟ دوباره بکشمش؟
Listen, I'm just a biochemist.
وش کن, من فقط يه بيوشيميستم
And most of the time I work in a glass jar and lead a very uneventful life.
بيشتر وقتم با لوله هاي آزمايشاهي سروکار داشتم و زندي بدون حادثه اي داشتم
I drive a Volvo, a beige one. But what I'm dealing with here...
من يه ولوو قهوه اي روشن ميرونم ...اما يزي که من اينجا باهاش سروکار دارم
is one of the most deadly substances the Earth has ever known.
يکي از مربارترين مواديه که تا حالا ديده شده
So what do you say you cut me some friggin' slack?
So what do you say you cut me some frig gin' slack?
A really elegant string-of-pearls configuration.
يه زنجيره زيباي مرواريدي شکل
Unfortunately, incredibly unstable.
متاسفانه بطور باورنکردني ناايداره
Well, what exactly does this stuff do?
خب,اين ماده دقيقا يکار ميکنه؟
If the rocket renders it aerosol, it can take out the entire city of people.
ار راکت آنرا در هوا خش کنه,ميتونه تمام مردم شهر رو درير کنه
Really? And what happens if you drop one?
واقعا؟ و ي ميشه اه يکي از اونها رو بندازي؟
Happily, it'll just wipe out you and me.
خوشبختانه, اون فقط من و تو رو نابود ميکنه
- How? - It's a cholinesterase inhibitor.
طوري؟ اون يه ماده مهارکننده کولين استراز هستش
Stops the brain from sending nerve messages down the spinal cord within 30 seconds.
اون ظرف 30 ثانيه انتقال يامهاي عصبي از مغز به طناب نخاعي را متوقف ميکنه
Any epidermal exposure or inhalation, and you'll know.
هرونه تماس وستي يا استنشاق آن, خودت خواهي فهميد
A twinge at the small of your back as the poison seizes your nervous system.
وقتي سم به سيستم عصبي حمله ميکنه درد شديدي در شت ايجاد ميکنه
Do not move that!
تکونش نده
Your muscles freeze, you can't breathe.
عضلاتت فلج ميشن و نميتوني نفس بکشي
You spasm so hard you break your own back, spit your guts out.
اساسمها بقدري شديده که کمرت ميخواد بشکنه و دل و رودت ميخواد بياد بيرون
But that's after your skin melts off.
بعد از تمام اينها وستت تاول ميزنه
My God.
خداي من
Oh, I think we'd like God on our side at the moment, don't you?
اوه,من فکر ميکنم در اين لحظه خدا در کنار ماست,مه نه؟
So what I'm doing now is removing the guidance system chips...
کاري که بايد بکنم اينه که ي سيستم هدايتي را بردارم
so the rocket will splash down after 500 feet.
بعدش راکت بعد از 500 ا ميترکه
All right, let me have that.
بسيارخب,بدش به من
You can let go of it. All right, just back away. Just back away!
ميتوني ولش کني. خيلي خب فقط عقب وايستا. فقط عقب وايستا
Sir, morgue team has not checked in.
قربان, تيم مستقر در سردخونه جواب نميده
Blackbird One, this is Blackbird. Over.
رنده سياه يک,رنده سياه هستم. تمام
Blackbird One, this is Blackbird. Come in, goddam it!
رنده سياه يک,رنده سياه هستم جواب بده, لعنتي
Somebody's still there. Let's move!
هنوز ينفر اينجاست بريم
Rats alive! Close on the morgue. Close on the morgue.
موشها زنده هستن! بريد سمت سردخونه بريد سمت سردخونه
Go, go, go, go, go, go, go.
بريد, بريد, بريد, بريد, بريد, بريد, بريد
Frye, Darrow, hustle up. We got more company!
فراي, داروو, ولشون بزنيد ما افراد بيشتري ميخوايم
Hold it.
صبرکن
Converge on the morgue. Move out.
توي سردخونه بهم ملحق بشيد حرکت کنيد
Goodspeed, come on. Come over here.
وود اسيد,زودباش دارن ميان اينجا
Good. I love pressure. I eat it for breakfast.
وود. من فشار رو دوست دارم من اونو صبحونه ميخورم
Come on. Time's up.
زودباش. وقت داره تموم ميشه
There's three rockets somewhere else. We have to find them.
سه تا راکت ديه باقي مونده.بايد اونها رو هم يدا کنيم
Come on!
زودباش
Clear!
امنه
I'm too old for this.
من براي اينکار خيلي يرم
- Where's it go? - I've no idea.
کجا داره ميره؟ نظري ندارم
Sir, all the guidance chips are gone.
قربان, تمام يهاي هدايتي رو بردن
Captain, I guess you didn't quite take care of the rat problem.
ايتان, حدث ميزنم شما تمام مراقبتهاي لازم در خصوص مشکل اون جونور رو انجام نداديد
- No, sir. - Well, there are two dead men here...
نه, قربان ...خب,دو تا جسد اينجا هستن
- who strongly suggest you go finish the job. - Yes, sir.
قويا توصيه ميکنم کارتون رو تموم کنيد بله, قربان
Yes, sir! Rio, Royce, let's go!
بله,قربان ريو, رويس,بريم
Move out!
راه بيفتيد
- You really don't know where this goes? - No, I don't know where it goes.
واقعا نميدوني اين کجا داره ميره؟ نه, نميدونم کجا داره ميره
Well, it's starting to pick up speed. Do you know how to slow it down?
خب, اون داره سرعت مييره ميدوني طوري ميشه سرعتش رو کم کرد؟
No, I don't.
نه, نميدونم
God.
خداي من
Mason, you all right?
ميسون, حالت خوبه؟
Yes, perfectly okay, you fucking idiot!
آره, کاملا خوبم تو يه احمق کله وکي
- They're coming. - Who?
دارن ميان کيا؟
- The Marines! - Where?
تفندارها کجان؟
- What the fuck's goin' on? - Let's cut him off.
ي شده؟ بذار ببرمش
No! No! No!
نه! نه! نه
Mason!
ميسون
I'm rather glad you didn't hesitate too long.
خوشحالم که زياد لفتش ندادي
How do you do it?
طوري اينکار رو ميکني؟
Oh, I was trained by the best. British Intelligence.
اوه, من توسط بهترينها ديدم سازمان جاسوسي انليس
Come on.
بريم
But in retrospect, I'd rather have been a poet or a farmer.
اه به عقب برميشتيم, من يه شاعر يا کشاورز ميشدم
Okay.
بسيارخب
Okay, the president arrives in three hours.
بسيارخب,رئيس جمهور تا 3 ساعت ديه ميرسن
His directive is to string Hummel along until the air strike is operational.
دستور ايشون کار کردن روي عمليات هامل هستش تا زمانيکه عمليات هوايي انجام بشه
- What's the word from Mohave, General? - The same as last time, Lou.
از موهاوه ه خبر, ژنرال؟ مثل دفعه آخري لوو
They're going as fast as they can.
اونا دارن با آخرين سرعت ممکن ميرن
- Do it over here. - On your knees. On your knees!
بيارش همينجا بشين رو زانوهات. بشين رو زانوهات
Navy SEALs, listen up. You've got something that belongs to me.
افراد نيروي دريايي, وش کنيد شما يزي رو که متعلق به من بوده را برداشتيد
Twelve guidance chips, to be precise.
دوازده تا ي هدايت کننده
Let me remind you there are lives at stake, civilian lives.
بذاريد بهتون يادآوري کنم که زنديها در خطرند,زندي غيرنظاميها
Speak up.
حرف بزن
- Speak up! - l, uh, uh...
...من, آه,آه
- Tell them your name. - My name is Larry Henderson.
اسمت رو بو اسم من لاري هندرسونه
- Oh, man. - And I'm a father of three.
اوه, مرد در 3 تا به هستم
And, uh, they've got a gun to my head.
و, آه, اونها يه تفن روي سرم ذاشتن
You've got exactly three minutes to return the guidance chips to the exercise yard...
...شما 3 دقيقه فرصت داريد تا اون يها رو برردونيد
- or Mr Henderson won't have a head. - Oh, no.
در غير اينصورت آقاي هندرسون خواهند مرد اوه, نه
Hey. Wha...
...هي.ي
Now, three to go.
حالا, 3 تا مونده
You find them and defuse them, okay?
اونها رو يدا کن و خنثاشون کن, باشه؟
- All right.
بسيارخب
I'll try and delay Hummel and give you more time.
سعي ميکنم همل رو سررم کنم تا تو وقت بيشتري داشته باشي
Hey, what about Mr Henderson's head?
هي, آقاي هندرسون ي ميشه؟
Okay? What do you mean?
باشه؟ منظورت يه؟
Okay.
باشه
- General. - Who the hell are you?
ژنرال تو کي هستي؟
I'm all that's left of the enemy.
من تنها بازمانده دشمن هستم
Bingo.
خودشه
Stand easy.
راحت باش
Thought I'd been in the service a long time.
فکر کنم مدت زمان طولاني خدمت کرده ام
- Name and rank, sailor. - Well, it's Army, actually.
اسم و درجت, ملوان خب, راستش, ارتشي هستم
Answer the question. And address him as "General, sir."
جواب سوال رو بده.و ايشون رو "جناب ژنرال" خطاب کن
Captain John Patrick Mason, General, sir,
کايتان جان اتريک ميسون جناب ژنرال
of Her Majesty's S.A.S. Retired, of course.
نيروي مخصوص مجستي البته بازنشسته شدم
You're a long way from home, Captain.
راه درازي رو اومدي, کايتان
How the hell are you involved in this?
طوري قاطي اين ماجرا شدي؟
Oh, I have a unique knowledge of this prison facility.
اوه, من اطلاعات منحصر بفردي از اين سلاحهاي سمي دارم
I was, uh, formerly a guest here.
من قبلا مهمان اينجا بودم
Hi, sweetie.
سلام, عزيزم
Hey, come back here, little boy.
هي, بررد اينجا,سر کوولو
Did they bother to tell you who I am, why I'm doing this?
اونا به خودشون زحمت دادن بن من کي هستم و را دارم اينکار رو ميکنم؟
Or are they just using you like they do everybody else?
يا اينکه اونها دارن مثل بقيه آدما از تو استفاده ميکنن؟
All I know is you were big in Vietnam. I saw the highlights on television.
تموم يزي که ميدونم اينه که شما فرد بزري در ويتنام بوديد افتخارات شما رو در تلويزيون ديدم
Then you wouldn't have any fuckin' idea what it means to lead some of the finest men...
س تو هي نظري نداري درباره اينکه طور ميشه ...بعضي از بهترين آدمها ميرن به سمتي که
on God's earth into battle, and then see their memory betrayed by their own fuckin' government.
زمين خدا رو بسمت جن ميبرن و اينکه طور به خاطره آنها بوسيله دولت لعنتيشون خيانت ميشه
I don't quite see how you cherish the memory of the dead...
من که اصلا نميبينم شما احترامي به ياد مردان داشته باشيد
by killing another million.
اونهم با کشتن ميليونها انسان ديه
And, uh, this is not combat.
و, آه,اين يک جن نيست
It's an act of lunacy, General, sir.
اين يک جنونه جناب ژنرال
Personally, I think you're a fuckin' idiot.
شخصا,فکر ميکنم شما يه آدم احمق هستيد
"The tree of liberty must be refreshed from time to time...
توماس جفرسون ميه: ...درخت آزادي بايد از زماني به زمان دير تجديد نيرو کنه
with the blood of patriots and tyrants." Thomas Jefferson.
با ريختن خون وطن رستان و ستمران
"Patriotism is the virtue of the vicious," according to Oscar Wilde.
:اسکار وايلد ميه ميهن رستي اک شدن از تبهکاريهاست
- Thank you for making my point. - Where are the guidance chips?
ممنون از اينکه منو متوجه کردي يهاي هدايت کننده کجان؟
- I destroyed them. - That was a bad move, soldier.
همشون رو ازبين بردم کار بدي کردي, سرباز
Does that mean you'll execute us both?
اين يعني اينکه هردوي ما رو ميکشيد؟
You're lucky that old man Hummel wants you alive.
شانس آوردي که هامل تو رو زنده ميخواد
'Cause I'll take pleasure in guttin' you, boy.
"
Boy
سر
What is wrong with these people, huh, Mason?
اين آدما شون شده, هاه,ميسون؟
Don't you think there's a lot of, uh, a lot of anger floatin' around this island?
فکر نميکني که خشم خيلي زيادي يرامون اين جزيره وجود داره؟
Kind of a pubescent volatility? Don't you think?
نوعي نوسان شرماهي؟ فکر نميکني؟
A lot of angst, a lot of, "I'm 16, I'm angry at my father" syndrome?
وحشت خيلي زياد, خيلي زياد, سندرم"من 16 سالمه,از دست درم عصباني هستم"؟
I mean, grow up! We're stuck on an island...
منظورم اينه که, بزر شو ...ما توي يه جزيره ير افتاديم
with a bunch of violence-for-pleasure-seeking psychopathic Marines.
با يه روه تفندار خشن روان ريش
Shame on them!
شرم بر اونها
Anyway, I only got one chem round. There's two left.
بهرحال,من فقط يکي از اون موشکها را يدا کردم دو تاي ديه مونده
- Mason? - Yes, I'm here.
ميسون؟ يه, من اينجام
I was just thinking how wonderful it was...
...داشتم فکر ميکردم قدر عجيب بود
when the inmates weren't allowed to talk in here.
که زندانيها اينجا اجازه حرف زدن نداشتند
Not allowed to talk.
اجازه حرف زدن نداشتند
How'd you do it?
طوري اينکار رو ميکردي؟
Uh, nurtured the hope that there was hope.
آه,اميد رو زنده نه ميداشتم اين اميد وجود داشت
That one day I'd breathe free air.
که يه روزي هواي آزاد استنشاق خواهم کرد
Perhaps meet my daughter.
شايدم دخترم رو ميديدم
Modest hopes, but, uh, they kept a man alive.
آه,اما همين اميدهاي کويک منو زنده نه داشت
What'd they put you away for, John?
ي شد که اونا تو رو کنار ذاشتن,جان؟
Oh, that's a long story.
اوه, داستانش طولانيه
Well, I'm not goin' anywhere.
خب, من نميخوام جايي برم
When was the last communication from our men on Alcatraz?
آخرين ارتباط ما با افرادمون در آلکاتراس کي بوده؟
Seven hours.
ساعت 7
Thermite plasma is operational.
لاسماي ترميت در مرحله عملياتيه
- Get me the president. - Be seated.
رئيس جمهور رو برام بير بفرماييد
Gentlemen, consider yourselves on ground alert. If we receive launch authority,
آقايون, توجهتون به هشدار زميني باشه اه مجوز حمله رو دريافت کنيم
your mission is the complete thermal destruction of Alcatraz Island.
ماموريت شما تخريب حرارتي کامل جزيره آلکاتراس ميباشه
The entire island is to be blanketed, not one square inch missed.
تمام جزيره بايد تحت وشش قرار بيره حتي 1 اين مربع هم نبايد جا بيفته
Eighty-one American civilians and a number of U.S. Marines...
هشتاد و يک شهروند آمريکايي و يه تعداد تفندار آمريکايي
will lose their lives in this air strike.
جونشون رو در اين حمله هوايي ازدست خواهند داد
Why didn't you just tell them where the microfilm was...
...را جاي ميکروفيلم رو به اونها نفتي
and, and create a solution?
و, و راه نجات يدا نکردي؟
Hmph. The moment they had the microfilm, they'd suicide me.
هه.اه دستشون به ميکروفيلم ميرسيد,سر منو زير آب ميکردن
- Some solution. - And you ended up here.
راه حل اينجا آخر خطه
Which brings me to another question. When you broke out...
...يه سوال ديه.وقتي تو شکست خوردي
Let me see if I can get this straight. You went down the incinerator chute,
بذار ببينم ميتونم اوضاع را درستش کنم تو رفتي توي کوره
on the mine cars, through the tunnels to the power plant,
"
under the steam engine... That was really cool, by the way.
زير موتور بخار... خيلي خنک بود,ضمنا
And into the cistern through the intake pipe.
و از طريق لوله ورودي به داخل آب انبار
But how, in the name of Zeus's butthole,
"
did you get out of your cell?
از سلولت خارج شدي؟
I only ask because in our current situation,
ميرسم براي اينکه در وضعيت فعلي ما
well, it could prove to be useful information, maybe!
خب, اون ميتونه براي اثبات اطلاعات مفيد باشه,شايد
Trade secrets, my son.
اسرار حرفه اي, سرم
Wow.
واو
General, two operational rockets left.
ژنرال, 2 تا راکت براي عمليات باقي مونده
One's at the lower lighthouse and there is one on the roof.
يکيشون توي فانوس درياييه و اون يکي روي شت بومه
And both of the birds are ready to fly, sir.
و هردوشون آماده شليک هستند, قربان
- G-General, can you hear me? - I heard you, Captain.
ژ-ژنرال, متوجه حرفاي من شديد؟ حرفات رو شنيدم, کايتان
Oh, just makin' sure.
اوه, فقط ميخواستم مطمئن بشم
Should we prepare for launch, General?
بايد آماده حمله باشيم,ژنرال؟
I'll handle the strategy, Captain.
فرماندهي با منه,کايتان
Yes, sir.
بله, قربان
The hour is approaching, sir. Just letting the General know of the time, sir.
زمان عمليات داره نزديک ميشه, قربان فقط ميخواستم ژنرال را در جريان زمان عمليات قرار بدم,قربان
- I'm very aware of the time, Captain. - Aye, aye, sir. Lettin' you know.
من کاملا در جريان زمان عمليات هستم,کايتان بله, بله, قربان. ميخواستم شما در جريان باشيد
Me and my boys are ready to cock, lock, and ready to rock.
من و افرادم آماده حمله هستيم
Mason, where're you going?
ميسون, کجا داري ميري؟
Thirty years ago I vowed I wouldn't die in this toilet.
سي سال قبل با خودم عهد کردم که توي اين مستراح نميرم
You're not leaving! There's a madman in there with his hand on a, on a button!
تو نميتوني بري!يه مرد ديوونه اينجاست که يه دکمه (شليک) توي دستشه
Shh. Some sniper's gonna get his ass.
شيش. ندتا تيرانداز ميزنن در کونش
Stop moving, Mason.
وايستا,ميسون
Mason, stop moving.
ميسون, وايستا
Hummel won't do it. He's a soldier, not a murderer.
هامل اينکار رو نميکنه اون يه سربازه, يه آدمکش نيست
- I read it in his eyes. - You read his eyes?
من اينو توي شماش ديدم توي شماش ديدي؟
Oh, well, then, everything's just fine!
اوه, خب س,همه يز مرتبه
- I can't afford to take that chance. - Why don't you talk louder?
من نميتونم تنهايي از عهدش بربيام را بلند حرف نميزني؟
Three minutes to go, sir.
سه دقيقه تا زمان عمليات قربان
- They're not gonna call, Frank. - Oh, they'll call.
اونا نميخوان تماس بيرن, فرانک اوه, اونا تماس مييرن
They'll call if we fire one of our rockets up their ass.
اه يکي از موشکها رو شليک کنيم باهامون تماس مييرن
Sir.
قربان
- Hummel. - Hi, Frank. It's Al Kramer here.
هامل هستم سلام, فرانک. ال کرامر اينجا هستن
- How's it going out there? - How do you think it's goin'?
اونجا ه خبره؟ تو ي فکر ميکني؟
- Listen, on this end we're gonna need another hour, Frank. - You've got three minutes.
وش کن, ما يک ساعت ديه وقت ميخوايم, فرانک شما 3 دقيقه فرصت داريد
Listen, uh, Frank, we have to get final authorization from the president.
وش کن, آه, فرانک, ما داريم آخرين مجوز رو از رئيس جمهور مييريم
Frank, please don't do anything stupid.
فرانک, لطفا کار احمقانه اي نکن
They want another hour.
اونا 1 ساعت ديه وقت ميخوان
Well, that's bullshit. That's bullshit, General. They're lyin'!
خب, مزخرفه مزخرفه, ژنرال.اونا دارن دروغ مين
They're calling our bluff, sir.
اونا دارن ما رو سرکار ميذارن,قربان
They're playing you for a fool, sir.
اونا دارن شما رو احمق فرض ميکنن,قربان
Order the launch, General.
دستور شليک بديد,ژنرال
Come on, General. Let's be all we can be.
زودباشيد,ژنرال بذاريد همونطوري که هستيم باشيم
The mission's not complete!
اين عمليات تموم نشده
Well, mine is.
خب, مال من تموم شده
When this is over, you'll go back home,
وقتي اين قضيه تموم بشه تو برميردي خونت
driving Carla and your baby insane in your beige Volvo.
و ولوو خاکستريت رو با کارلا و بت ميروني
And I'll be dead or back in prison, which is the same thing.
و درهرحال,يا من ميميرم يا برميردم زندون
You're not leaving.
تو جايي نميري
All right, I'll do it myself.
خيلي خب خودم انجامش ميدم
I got three weeks' weapons training.
من 3 هفته آموزش اسلحه ديده ام
I'll kick the... Out of a platoon full of Marines.
من خودم خدمت تنفندارها ميرسم
No problem.
مشکلي نيست
- Major, patch me into Roof Battery. - Aye, sir.
سررد, منو به راکت شت بوم وصل کن بله, قربان
Fire open control circuit coordinates to the roof, sir.
هماهني با راکت مستقر در شت بام انجام شد, قربان
Let's go!
بريم
Laser powered up!
برق وصل شد
- Oh, no. - I said, on your knees!
اوه, نه فتم, بشين رو زانوهات
My name's Stanley Goodspeed. I'm a chemical weapons specialist for the FBl.
اسم من استلي وود اسيده.من متخصص سلاحهاي شيمايي اف بي آي هستم
- Uh, glass or plastic? - What?
آه, شيشه يا لاستيک؟ ي؟
- Glass or plastic? Glass or plastic? - Shut the fuck up!
شيشه يا لاستيک؟ شيشه يا لاستيک؟ جلوي شليک اون لعنتي رو بير
Because if the winds change after you launch those rockets,
ون بعد از شليک راکت اه جهت باد تغيير کنه
- we're all gonna die. - Shut up!
هممون خواهيم مرد خفه شو
And you're gonna end up in either a glass jar or a plastic bag.
و تو ميخواي آخر عاقبتت توي يه جام شيشه اي يا کيسه لاستيکي باشه؟
So, what do you say you do the math, h-hand over the gun...
...خب,نظرت يه که دستت رو از روي تفن برداري
- and let's go find some rockets? - I said shut the fuck...
و بذاري بقيه راکتها رو يدا کنم؟ ...بهت فتم خفه شو
- You made the right choice. - I decided I didn't want your child...
انتخاب درستي کردي ...من اينکار رو کردم براي اينکه نميخواستم
growing up without a father.
بت بدون در بزر بشه
Hey, the last time I swam this channel I was your age.
هي,آخرين باري که توي اين کانال شنا کردم همسن تو بودم
So, I'm fucked either way. So, come on.
خب, من دخل اون کانال رو آوردم س, عجله کن
Weapon is hot. I am standing by for the launch command.
سلاح آماده شليکه.من منتظر دستور شليک هستم
Man, killing Navy SEALs is one thing...
...مرد,کشتن نيروهاي ويژه دريايي يه يزه
- Is this for real? - Hey, it's business.
واقعا ميخواي اينکار رو بکني؟ هي, اين تجارته
Access code entered. Weapon available for release.
کد دسترسي وارد شد سلاح آماده شليکه
Launch coordinates: six, seven,
:مختصات شليک شش, هفت
five, four, five, niner.
نج, هار, نج نه
The weapon is hot. I'm standing by for launch command.
سلاح آماده شليکه.منتظر دستور شليک هستم
That's affirmative.
کد درسته
Standing by for command.
منتظر دستور شليک هستم
I'm waiting for launch command, General.
منتظر دستور شليک هستم, ژنرال
- Fire. - Fire!
آتش
Missile loose!
موشک شليک شد
Origin: Alcatraz, 67253725.
مبداء: آلکاتراس,67253725
- What's the goddam heading? - Heading 185 degrees south southeast.
مسير حرکت موشک؟ مسير 185 درجه جنوب جنوب شرقي
- Speed? - Three hundred knots. It's headed right at Oakland.
سرعت؟ سيصد نات مسيرش مستقيم به سمت اوکلنده
Football game.
بازي شروع شد
Oh, my God.
اوه, خداي من
Missile radically changing direction.
موشک داره تغيير جهت ميده
New direction: 275 degrees west. It's headed out to sea, sir.
مسير جديد:275 درجه غربي اون به سمت دريا تغيير جهت داد, قربان
Oh, Christ!
اوه, يا عيسي مسيح
Missile losing altitude. Falling.
موشک داره ارتفاع کم ميکنه داره سقوط ميکنه
Falling, 300 feet, 200, 100.
در حال سقوط, 300 ا, 200, 100
Bogey detonated under water.
موشک دشمن زير آب منفجر شد
- What the fuck? - It missed.
ي شد؟ ازدست داديمش
- Well, that's great. - Extremely great.
خب, عاليه فوق العادست
But there's still one left.
اما هنوز يکي ديه مونده
What happened to the rocket? What the fuck happened to the coordinates?
ه اتفاقي براي راکت افتاد؟ ه اتفاقي براي مختصات داده شده افتاد؟
What the fuck is going on? Sir! Major!
ه اتفاقي داره ميوفته؟ قربان! جناب سررد
- Captain, step outside. - Talk to me, sir.
ايتان, بريد بيرون به من بيد, قربان
Captain, step outside!
کايتان, بريد بيرون
Get me the Pentagon.
نتاون رو برام بير
What the hell was that, Frank?
اون ه کاري بود,فرانک؟
- I said, what the hell... - I heard what you said! If you're gonna be insubordinate,
..بهت فتم اون ه کاري شنيدم ي فتي! اه بخواي از دستورات سريي کني
- I'd appreciate it if you'd do it with a little more respect. - Cut the crap, General.
ممنون ميشم اه مودب تر صحبت کني - تعارف رو بذار کنار, ژنرال
- What the hell are you doing? - I'm not ready to kill these people.
ه غلطي داري ميکني؟ من نميتونم اون آدما رو بکشم
- Call the Pentagon. Ask for more time. - No!
زن بزن نتاون. ازشون وقت بيشتري بير نه
Do it, Frank! We're coming loose.
يالا, فرانک ما داريم ميبازيم
You're coming loose. The rest of us are in complete control.
تو داري ميبازي.همه ي تحت کنترله
- We're askin' 'em. We're askin' 'em for a new deadline. - Put the phone down.
ما بهشون يه ضرب العجل تازه ميديم وشي رو بذار
- The men are falling apart. - The men are Marines!
افرادمون دارن جدا ميشن اون آدما تفنداران دريايي هستن
Are they?
واقعا؟
- I wanna talk to General Kramer. - You've been asked by an old friend.
ميخوام با ژنرال کرامر صحبت کنم يه دوست قديمي ازت ميخواد
- Put him on the phone right now. - You've been ordered by a superior officer.
همين الان اون وشي رو بذار افسر مافوقت بهت دستور ميده
- This is Major Baxter. - Now you're being given your last chance by a man with a gun.
سررد باکستر هستم حالا آخرين شانست توسط يه مرد اسلحه بدست بهت داده ميشه
Put the phone down.
وشي رو بذار
- I thought you weren't ready to kill. - I'm warmin' up.
فکر ميکردم آماده کشتن نيستي دارم بهت هشدار ميدم
At ease.
آزاد
They need a decision, Mr President.
تصميم بيريد رئيس جمهور
These past few hours...
...اين ند ساعت ذشته
have been the longest, darkest of my life.
طولاني ترين و تاريک ترين لحظات زندي من بودن
How does one weigh human life?
ارزش زندي انسان قدره؟
One million civilians against 81 hostages.
يک ميليون شهروند درمقابل 81 روان
And in the middle, Frank Hummel.
و اين وسط,فرانک هامل
That we have ignored, abandoned or marginalized...
...که ما ناديده رفتيم و بهش کم توجهي کرديم
a great soldier like Frank Hummel,
يک سرباز بزر مثل فرانک هامل
and that American boys have paid for that neglect in blood...
...و اون فرزندان آمريکايي که از جون مايه ذاشتن
is equally real and equally tragic.
واقعي و حزن انيزه
We are at war with terror.
ما در حال جن با آدمکشي هستيم
Fighting a war means casualties.
جن هم تلفاتي داره
This is the worst call I've ever had to make.
اين بدترين تصميميه که تاحالا رفتم
Air strike approved.
اجازه حمله هوايي داده ميشه
Red Thunder to tower. Request clearance.
از تندر قرمز به برج مراقبت اجازه رواز داريد
With the amount of firepower they're gonna drop in there,
با اين مقدار قدرت آتشي که اونجا ريخته ميشه
- Tower this is Strike Leader. Prepared to go. - it'll be over in a few seconds.
برج مراقبت فرمانده حمله هوايي صحبت ميکنه آماده رفتن باشيد همه ي ظرف ند ثانيه تموم ميشه
Flight time to drop point: 17 minutes.
:زمان رواز تا نقطه موردنظر هفده دقيقه
Excuse me, General, sir, with all due respect to you, but what the fuck is going on?
عذرخواهي ميکنم جناب ژنرال با عرض احترام,ه اتفاقي داره ميوفته؟
- You changed the coordinates, didn't you, General? - That's affirmative, Captain.
شما مختصات رو تغيير داديد,مه نه, ژنرال؟ بله, کايتان
So, now they think we're gutless, the Feds? They think we won't actually do it.
خب, حالا اونا فکر ميکنن ما بزدليم, مه نه؟ اونا فکر ميکنن ما واقعا نميتونيم اينکار رو بکنيم
They're gonna come at us with everything they've got. Air and sea.
اونا با تمام قوا ميان سراغمون از هوا و دريا
- They're gonna bomb our ass back to the Stone Age. - They don't know we missed on purpose.
اونا ما رو بمباران ميکنن اونا نميدونن ما عمدا خطا کرديم
Great. We're not gutless, we're incompetent. That right?
عاليه. ما بزدل نيستيم,ما بي کفايت هستيم. مه نه؟
I don't think I like your tone, Captain. We planned for this contingency.
از نحوه حرف زدنت خوشم نمياد,کايتان ما براي اين احتمال طرح داشتيم
Load the V.X. into the choppers, take four hostages and evacuate.
ازهاي وي ايکس رو بار هليکوترها کنيد هار تا از روانها رو برداريد و بريد
The consequences of our actions I'll face alone.
عواقب کارهامون تنها به عهده منه
Excuse me, General, but what about the fucking money?
ببخشيد, ژنرال, ول ي ميشه؟
There is no fucking money. Mission's over.
ولي درکار نيست عمليات تموم شد
Bullshit it's over.
به جهنم که تموم شد
You're talking to a General, soldier. Maintain discipline.
تو داري با يه ژنرال صحبت ميکني,سرباز. ادب رو رعايت کن
I'm not a soldier, Major.
من سرباز نيستم, سررد
The day we took hostages we became mercenaries. And mercenaries get paid!
روزي که روان رفتيم تبديل شديم به مزدور مزدورها هم با ول کار ميکنن
I want my fucking money!
من ولم رو ميخوام
This mission was based on the threat of force.
اين عمليان بر اساس تهديد بوده
I'm not about to kill 80,000 innocent people. Do you think I'm out of my fucking mind?
من نيومدم که 80000 آدم بيناه رو بکشم فکر ميکني عقلم رو ازدست دادم
We bluffed. They called it. The mission's over.
ما بلوف زديم. اونا رفتنش عمليات تموم شد
Whoever said anything about bluffing, General?
کي درباره بلوف زدن صحبت کرد, ژنرال؟
Stand down, Captain.
وايستا عقب, کايتان
Major, I'm ordering you to take these men to the choppers and evacuate.
سررد, بهت دستور ميدم اين افراد رو سوار هليکوتر کني و از اينجا خارج بشي
- That's a simple order, Major! - It's not so simple, Frank.
اين يه دستور سادست, سررد خيلي هم ساده نيست, فرانک
Sergeant Crisp,
سرروهبان کريس
secure the General.
ژنرال رو همراهي کن
I'm relieving you of your command, sir.
من شما رو از فرماندهي برکنار ميکنم, قربان
Sergeant!
سرروهبان
- I'll have that sidearm, sir. - You mean this sidearm?
دستتون رو بديد به من, قربان منظورت اين دستمه
Major Baxter, you're either with us or against us.
ژنرال باکستر, يا با مايي يا عليه ما
It has been the greatest honour of my life to serve with you, General.
بالاترين افتخار زندي من اينه که در کنار شما باشم,ژنرال
But like he said,
اما همانطور که اون فت
it's over.
همه ي تموم شد
Let's get him.
بريم بيريمش
Mason!
ميسون
- My God, what have I done? - Where's the last rocket? Where's the last rocket?
خداي من, من يکار کردم؟ آخرين راکت کجاست؟
- Lower lighthouse.
ايين فانوس دريايي
- Go!
برو
Darrow, go to the lighthouse. I'll take care of this fucker!
دارف, برو به فانوس دريايي من مراقب اين عوضي هستم
One, two, three! Eat that!
يک, دو, سه بيرش
Did it.
انجام شد
Come here. Come here, you little chicken shit!
بيا اينجا. بيا اينجا جوجه کووله عوضي
You shoot me, I drop this. We're both dead.
اه بهم شليک کني,اينو ميندازم هر دومون ميميريم
Well, come on. Come on. Don't be scared. I won't hurt ya.
خب, يالا. يالا. نترس. بهت آسيبي نميرسونم
- Come on. - Do you know how this shit works?
يالا ميدوني کار اين يه؟
Come on. Come on.
يالا. يالا
I don't need the gun. I'll put it down.
من تفن لازم ندارم اونو ميندازمش زمين
Come on, let's play. Come on. Come on.
بيا,بازي کنيم يالا. يالا
Listen, I think we got started off on the wrong foot. Stan Goodspeed, FBl. Uh...
وش کن, فکر ميکنم ما اشتباهي شروع کرديم ...استن وود اسيد, اف بي آي.آه
Let's talk music. Do you like the Elton John song, "Rocket Man"?
بيا درباره موسيقي حرف بزنيم. از آهن آلتون جان خوشت مياد,"راکت من"؟
I don't like soft-ass shit.
من از اون عوضي خوشم نمياد
Oh, you... Oh, oh. Oh.
اوه, تو... اوه, اوه اوه
Well, I only bring it up because, uh, it's you.
خب, من فقط اونو بالا ميارم براي اينکه, آه, اون تويي
You're the Rocket Man.
تو "راکت من" هستي
No!
نه
- How do you like how that shit works? - Second rocket's away!
دوست داري بدوني اين ه طوري کار ميکنه؟ راکت دوم شليک شد
It splashed into the bay, sir. No detonation.
اون بداخل خليج افتاد,قربان بدون انفجار
Shit!
لعنتي
Darrow!
دارف
Open up!
بازکن
Come on.
يالا
Hey, you mother!
هي, بيرش
Oh, I'm gonna get you now, baby.
اوه, ميخوام بيرمت,به
Okay.
خيلي خب
I got ya. I got you, baby.
رفتمت رفتمت, به
Come on.
يالا
Fucker!
لعنتي
Red Thunder Strike Leader.
فرمانده حمله تندر قرمز صحبت ميکنه
Time on target: seven minutes.
:زمان رسيدن به هدف هفت دقيقه
English prick. I tell you my old man was Irish?
بهت فتم يرمرد من ايرلندي بود؟
Maintain air speed 450 knots.
سرعت رو روي 450 نات حفظ کنيد
Fuck!
لعنتي
It's me and you, pal.
فقط منو تو هستيم, رفيق
I want that fucking chip!
من اون ي لعنتي رو ميخوام
I love pressure.
من عاشق سختي هستم
I know you're in here, and I know you can hear me.
ميدونم اينجايي,ميدونم که صدام رو ميشنوي
Now, pay the piper and come out like a man.
بي مايه فطيره مثل يه مرد بيا بيرون
Increase speed to 500 knots.
سرعت رو به 500 نات افزايش بديد
You motherfucker! Die!
لعنتي بمير
I'm gonna choke my million bucks out of you. You're gonna die.
ميخواي بميري
Eat that, you fuck!
بخورش, به ا رفتي
All right, team, inbound. Time on target: 60 seconds.
بسيارخب, تيم,وارد محدوده شديم زمان رسيدن به هدف: 60 ثانيه
Come to course heading 142 degrees.
تغيير جهت به 142 درجه
When he neutralizes the threat,
وقتي تهديد رو خنثي کرديم
we launch green flares and we wait for the cavalry.
منور سبز شليک ميکنيم و منتظر نيروي کمکي ميشيم
- Let's tighten up that formation. - May God have mercy on your souls.
آرايش جني بيريد خداوند شما را رحمت کند
Please don't let this happen. There has to be something you can do. Please.
لطفا نذاريد اين اتفاق بيوفته.حتما يه کاري از دستتون برمياد.خواهش ميکنم
Let's drop to the deck. One hundred feet below radar.
از ايين ل عبور ميکنيم يکصد ا زير رادار
Target acquired. Rolling in.
هدف شناسايي شد رفت به حافظه
This is Red Thunder. Master armed. Master armed.
تندر قرمز صحبت ميکنه مسلح بشيد. مسلح بشيد
Time on target: 12 seconds.
:زمان رسيدن به هدف دوازده ثانيه
T.O.T.: ten seconds.
ده ثانيه
Stay tight, gentlemen.
محکم بشينيد, آقايون
I got green smoke. I got green smoke!
من دود سبز ميبينم
This is C.Q. One, C.Q. One! Green smoke! We have green smoke! Over.
سي کيو يک صحبت ميکنه, سي کيو يک!دود سبز ما دود سبز رو ميبينيم! تمام
- Eh, gimme that! Gimme that! Abort! - Abort!
آه, بزنيد! بزنيد! دست نه داريد!دست نه داريد
- Flight leader, abort, abort, abort! - Jesus Chri...
مسئول رواز, دست نه داريد,دست نه داريد,دست نه داريد ...يا عيسي مسيح
I already dropped them!
من جلوتر بمبها را انداختم
- Oh, goddam it! - Oh, my God!
اوه, لعنتي اوه, خداي من
Get out of my way. Let me through, please. Let me through!
از سر راه بريد کنار. اجازه بديد,لطفا. اجازه بديد
The cells did not get hit. The bombs hit on the back of the island.
سلولهاي زندان آسيب نديدن بمبها به شت جزيره اصابت کردن
I'm fed up saving your ass. I'm amazed you ever got past puberty.
من حوصله نجات زندي تو رو ندارم :ترجمه و تنظيم hamilton hamilton37@37.com
I suppose all this will make a great bedtime story to tell your kid.
بنظر من تمام اين وقايع يه داستان فوق العاده ميشه که ميتوني موقع خواب براي بت تعريف کني
You're insane, Mason. The kid'll have nightmares. Spend all my money on shrinks.
تو دويوونه اي, ميسون اين به کابوس ميبينه
Goodspeed, come in.
وود اسيد, جواب بده
Goodspeed, Goodspeed, do you read me? Come in!
وود اسيد, وود اسيد صداي منو ميشنوي؟ جواب بده
- Scanning all radio frequencies. - Goodspeed, do you read me? Come in!
تمام فرکانسهاي راديويي رو اسکن کنيد وود اسيد, صداي منو ميشنوي؟ جواب بده
Goodspeed, do you read me? Come in!
وود اسيد, صداي منو ميشنوي؟ جواب بده
This is Goodspeed.
وود اسيد صحبت ميکنه
- Are the hostages alive? - Every one of 'em.
آيا روانها زنده هستن؟ همشون زنده هستن
Goodspeed, it's Womack.
وود اسيد, ووماک هستم
What about Mason?
از ميسون ه خبر؟
- He's dead, sir. - How? When?
اون مرد, قربان طوري؟ کي؟
Just come and get me.
فقط بياييد منو از اينجا ببريد
Womack tore up your pardon, John.
ووماک حکم عفو تو رو اره کرد,جان
But, of course. I knew he would.
البته ميدونستم که اين کار رو ميکنه
The S.D.U.s and the scuba gear should still be where we came ashore.
موتورهاي زير آبي بايد همونجا کنار ساحل باشن
If you can get to the Pan Pacific Hotel, there's clothes in my closet, $200 in the Bible.
اه بتوني به هتل ن سيفيک بري,توي نجه, لباسهاي من هستش دويست دلار هم لاي کتاب مقدس هستش
Room 26.
اتاق 26
Well, it's been a long time since I've said thank you to anybody.
خب,از آخرين باري که از کسي تشکر کردم مدت زمان زيادي ميذره
But thank you.
اما ازت ممنونم
Well, Stanley, uh, this is when we go our separate ways, huh?
خب, استنلي,آه,وقتشه که راهمون رو از هم جدا کنيم, هاه؟
But, uh, I'm sure you know the etymology of your name "Goodspeed."
اما, آه,مطمئنم که ميدوني ريشه اسمت "وود اسيد" يه
Yeah, Godspeed: to wish someone a prosperous journey. Why?
آره, وود اسيد يعني: آرزوي سفري موفق براي کسي داشتن را رسيدي؟
Well, if you fancy a journey,
...خب, اه خيال سفر داشتي
I recommend Fort Walton, Kansas.
من بهت فورت والتون ايالت کانزاس رو يشنهاد ميکنم
I was thinking of Maui.
من داشتم به هاوايي فکر ميکردم
No.
نه
Forget Maui.
هاوايي رو فراموش کن
St Michael's Church, Fort Walton, Kansas.
کليساي مايکل فورت والتون, ايالت کانزاس
Front pew, right leg.
نيمکت جلويي, سمت راست
Hollow.
ول خوردي
Is this what I think it is?
اين همون يزيه که من فکر ميکنم؟
Mason?
ميسون؟
- Congratulations, Dr Goodspeed. You did it. - Thank you, sir.
تبريک ميم, دکتر وود اسيد تو موفق شدي ممنون, قربان
You know, for a while there, I didn't think you were gonna make it.
ميدوني, وقتي اونجا بودي فکر نميکردم بتوني از عهدش بربيايي
Well done, son.
کارت خوب بود, سر
So, where's Mason?
خب, ميسون کجاست؟
Vaporized. Blown out to sea.
بخار شد افتاد توي دريا
Blown out to sea, huh?
افتاد توي دريا, هاه؟
Yeah.
آره
Poor bastard.
دروغوي کوولو
Goodspeed, where's Mason? Where's his body? I wanna see that son of a bitch!
وود اسيد, ميسون کجاست؟ جسدش کجاست؟ من ميخوام اون حرومزاده رو ببينم
Vaporized, sir. Excuse me, gentlemen.
بخار شد, قربان ببخشيد, آقايون
What? Vaporized? A body can vaporize?
ي؟ بخار شد؟ جسد ميتونه بخار بشه؟
Oh, yeah! Absolutely, sir.
اوه, بله کاملا, قربان
St Michael's Church, front pew, right leg.
کليساي مايکل فورت والتون, ايالت کانزاس
Front pew, right leg.
نيمکت جلويي, سمت راست
Vandals! Vandals!
وندالس! وندالس
Oh, yes, baby, come on!
اوه, عجله کن, سر
- Stop! Vandals! Stop! - I'm sorry!
صبرکن! وندالس! صبرکن متاسفم
- Come on, baby! - I've got it! Okay, let's go!
زودباش, سر رفتمش! خيلي خب, بزن بريم
- Stop! Stop! - Sorry!
وايستيد! وايستيد متاسفم
Stop! Hey, hey, you!
وايستيد! هي, هي, تو
Vandals! Vandals!
وندالس! وندالس
Honey, uh, you wanna know who really killed J.F.K.?
عزيزم,ميخواي بدوني کي واقعا جان اف کندي رو کشت؟